睜開你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
睜開你的…
Open your...
睜開你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
大衛，睜開你的...
David, open your...
那麼, 我猜
空蕩的街道意味著孤獨吧
Well, I suppose
the empty street meant loneliness.
你是個精神病專家,應該有更好的分析
You're a shrink.
You gotta do better than that.
我是個醫生, 我倆別互相存有偏見
I'm a doctor.
Let's not stereotype each other.
不是所有的有錢少爺都空虛...
Not all rich kids
are soulless and...
也不是所有的心理醫生都會解夢
not all psychologists
care about dreams.
問題是你怎麼會在這裡, 為什麼會被指控
The question is how you got here
and why you've been charged.
你想知道什麼? 我快滿33歲了
What do you want to know?
I was about to turn 33.
擁有三家雜誌社和一家全球性的出版社
I ran three magazines
and a worldwide publishing house.
大部分日子裡我都愚昧的認為這一切都是永恆的
Most days I fooled myself into
believing it would last forever.
年輕不都是這樣嗎?
Isn't that what being young
is about?
自以為你就是...
Believing secretly
that you would be...
歷史上唯一的那個...
the one person
in the history of man...
長生不老的人
who would live forever.
你這麼早去哪兒?
Where you going so early?
別再往我的鬧鐘裡錄留言了, 好嗎?
Don't record any more messages
on my alarm clock, okay?
- 為什麼?
- 我會以為我們結婚了
- Why not?
- I'll start to think we're married.
別再提那個字眼, 我就不來這裡...
Don't ever say that word.
I will never come over...
給你帶雞湯, 又讓你欲仙欲死
and bring you chicken soup
and fuck your brains out again.
你感冒好了嗎?
How's your cold?
還沒, 你呢?
Still there.
How 'bout yours?
你真的讓我忘了自己在生病
You definitely took
my mind off it.
真的嗎?
Really?
Yes!
我是茱莉
"Juliana" here.
嗨, 蕾娜, 我錯過試鏡了, 我一定是瘋了!
Hi, Rayna. I missed my audition.
I lost my head!
不, 聽著, 我得掛了
No, listen, I have to go.
我在大衛這兒
I'm with David.
你自便吧, 瑪麗亞會來清理, 你走前設定警鈴
Help yourself to whatever. Maria will
clean up. Set the alarm before you go.
還有...
And...
你是最棒的
you are the greatest.
拜拜，甜心
Bye, honey.
拜拜，甜心, 我額...再打給你
I'll call you later.
幾時?
When?
-幾時?
-很快!
- When?
- Soon!
你訂了球場沒有?
Did you reserve the court?
鎮定, 這種時候我應付不了這麼複雜的會談
Easy. I can't handle heavy
conversation at this ungodly hour.
抱歉這麼早做這些, 但我十點要打完
Sorry to do this early,
but I gotta be done by 10:00.
你八點四十五趕不到了, 是嗎?
You're not gonna make
the 8.:45, are you?
-你怎麼找到我的?
-大衛埃姆斯...
- How did you find me?
- David Aames...
你要決定新一期的封面顏色
you have to check the colors
for the new issue of Rise.
- 有什麼顏色?
- 黃, 紅或傳統的白色
- What are the colors?
- Yellow and red or traditional white.
- 我得想想看
- 大衛, 拜託
- Gotta think about it.
- David, please.
別遲到十點的董事會
Don't be late for the 10.:00
with the board.
好的, 但別告訴別人我在哪, 上帝打來我也不管
Don't tell anybody where I am.
I don't care if God calls.
- 我很忙, 非常忙
- Yeah
- I'm very, very busy.
- Yeah.
- 你就不能廢掉董事會嗎?
- 那七個小矮人? 不行
- Can't you get rid of that board?
- The Seven Dwarfs? No.
那些人快把你逼瘋了
Those people drive you nuts.
這是我老爸的意願, 他雇傭了他們
And that was the desire
of my father who hired them.
你又上了茱莉吉雅妮, 是嗎?
You fucked Julie Gianni again,
didn't you?
打電話時我就知道某人在
I know someone was there
when I called.
你還用那種語氣
You had that tone.
"沒啦，我感冒, 晚上想待在家."
"No, I got a cold.
I'm hanging in tonight, you know."
我真的感冒了
I had a cold.
- 只有我一個人
- 好吧.
- I was alone.
- Fine.
- 這輩子你愛怎樣就怎樣
- 謝謝.
- You do what you want with your life.
- Thanks.
但有一天你會知道真愛是什麼
But one day you'll know
what love truly is.
它夾雜著心酸和甜蜜
It's the sour and the sweet.
我嘗過心酸, 它讓我領會到甜蜜的滋味
I know sour, which allows me
to appreciate the sweet.
茱莉吉雅妮只是朋友
Julie Gianni is a friend.
有時候我們一起上床
Sometimes we sleep together.
幹嘛? 幹嘛?
What? What?
- 幹嘛?
- 我的夢中情人...
- What?
- My dream girl...
茱莉吉雅妮...
Julie Gianni...
竟然是你的...炮友
is your fuck buddy.
- 你想聽什麼?
- 開慢點, 老兄
- What do you wanna listen to?
- Slow down, man.
有什麼聽的?
巴塞隆納...盧珀...
What do we got here?
Barcelona, Looper.
電臺司令?
Radiohead?
小心! 小心!
Look out! Look out!
操！
Fuck!
我們差點沒命
We almost died.
- 我知道
- 你們他媽的看著點!
- I know.
- Use your fuckin' head!
死亡就擺在我面前, 知道我看見什麼嗎?
My own death was in front of me,
and you know what happened?
你的一生從我眼前閃過
Your life flashed
before my eyes.
- 怎麼樣?
- 很值得為此死去
- How was it?
- Almost worth dying for.
我們到大門了, 正準備上去
We're at the front door.
We're coming up now.
- 早安，老闆, 睡得好吧?
- 是的, 很好
- Good morning, sir. Sleep well?
- Yes, I did.
- 吃早餐了嗎?
- 什麼?
- Eaten yet?
- What's that?
- 吃了嗎？
- 沒有
- Eaten yet?
- No.
- 早上好
- 大衛, 你居然跑去打壁球, 我替你拖了一個鐘頭
- Good morning.
- David, you were playing racquetball.
I've been covering you for an hour.
我救了你的命, 而你竟然去打球
I'm saving your ass
and you're playing racquetball.
謝謝你, 弗裡茨
Thank you, Fritz.
我們出電梯了, 董事會很不爽
We are now exiting the elevator.
The board is not happy.
- 早, 碧翠西
- 你好, 大衛
- Good morning, Beatrice.
- Hello, David.
你今天終於來了, 寇特妮想要你回復她的郵件
You're in the Post today. Courtney Love
called to see if you got her E-mail.
浮華世界主編想約你吃晚飯
And Graydon Carter and Shelley Wanger
called to see if dinner's still on.
- 不錯
- 美術部要你決定顏色...
- Cool.
- Art department needs the colors-
- 黃, 紅或白?
- 早上好, 大衛
- yellow and red or white?
- Good morning, David.
我有提到董事會對你遲到很生氣嗎?
And did I mention the board
is pissed you're late?
嗨, 大衛, 等一下!
Hey, David! Hold up!
哪一個?
Which one?
等等, 這個嗎? 大衛!
Wait. This one?
David!
好了, 他們都在等你
Okay, they're all waiting for you.
- 你換了髮型
- 是的. 大衛...
- You changed your hair.
- Yes. And David...
做好被批鬥的準備
opinions are expected.
你夢見過董事會...那七個你稱為小矮人的嗎?
Do you dream about the board-
the Seven Dwarfs as you call them?
噴嚏精, 害羞鬼...
Sneezy, Bashful...
瞌睡蟲...
Sleepy...
開心果...
Happy...
萬事通...
Doc...
糊塗蛋...
Dopey...
當然, 還有暴躁鬼
and of course, Grumpy.
艾斯本好玩嗎?
How was Aspen?
不錯
Good.
現在, 我要答案，馬上就要
Now, I want answers
and I want them now.
進展如何?
How's it going?
他們還把我當十一歲小孩
They still look at me
as if I was 11 years old.
他將繼承一切
He's going to inherit everything.
全都是他的
He gets it all.
你很怕你的夢, 不是嗎?
You're scared of your dreams,
aren't you?
無論怎樣這是一場噩夢
It's a nightmare either way.
這就是對你所發生的一切的解釋?
Is that how you explain
what's happened to you?
- 什麼?
- 你的臉怎麼了?
- What?
- What happened to your face?
- 我不再跟你談了
- 你不敢給我看你的臉?
- I'm not talking to you anymore.
- You don't wanna show me your face?
是的!
No!
- 你知道為什麼你會在這裡嗎?
- 聊天, 喝咖啡...
- Do you know why you're here?
- Conversation, the coffee-
大衛, 那些你來我往的交談...
David, the part where
we parry and joust...
逐漸互相瞭解...
and get to know each other
bit by bit-
已經, 不管用了
No. No can do.
我們得跳過這些, 因為你已被控謀殺
We'll have to skip that because
you've been charged with murder.
四周後, 法官會決定你的命運...
In four weeks, a judge
will determine your fate...
依據是我的診斷報告
based on what I write.
- 你最好告訴我
- 根本沒有殺人
- So you will talk to me.
- There is no murder.
根本沒殺人!
There is no murder!
根本沒發生過!
It never happened!
- 我不必跟任何人談!
- 要我幫忙嗎?
- I don't have to talk to anybody!
- Want me to help?
- 滾我遠點
- 冷靜點,年輕人
- Get the fuck away from me.
- You take it easy, sunshine.
冷靜點, 面具, 你的整個故事都是漏洞!
Take it easy, Face.
Your whole story's full of holes!
別說了. 別說了!
Stop. Stop!
請立刻離開這裡, 這裡我負責
Please leave right now.
I'll take responsibility.
請立刻離開這裡, 他已受到控制了
Please leave right now.
He's got control.
我會再找你的，靠老爸的怪胎
I'm gonna get you,
daddy's boy little freak.
- 我父母都死了，你這混蛋!
- 夠了!
- My parents are dead, you fuck!
- Enough!
真的嗎?
Is that true?
- 好員警, 壞員警...
- 你真的只靠你老爸嗎?
- Good cop, bad cop-
- That you're a daddy's boy?
大衛.埃姆斯.西尼爾的一生
Primer on David Aames Senior.
我父親不是屬於二十一世紀的人
My father wasn't built
for the 21 st century.
他從不去麥當勞, 從不
He never went to McDonald's,
not once.
也不看電視
He never watched television,
and yet...
他最喜歡的雜誌仍然是電視週刊
his biggest magazine
is still the TVDigest.
他和我母親常舉行大型的文學派對
He and my mother threw the grandest
parties of the literary world.
熱氣球, 高空跳傘
Ballooned.
Jumped out of airplanes.
他追求冒險
He sought adventure.
他的自傳是...
His autobiography is the manual...
紐約所有殘酷競爭的出版商的指南
for every cutthroat publisher
in New York City.
書名叫"捍衛王國"
It's called Defending the Kingdom.
我讀過
I've read it.
第127頁
Page 127-
"小大衛是個可愛的孩子"
"David Jr. was a delight
as a child."
我有漏掉什麼嗎? 這就是他寫的所有關於你的?
Did I miss something here?
Was that all he wrote about you?
我覺得他一直不能原諒這個事實...
I don't think he ever
got over the fact...
我有十分...
that I'm absolutely...
嚴重的懼高症
terrified of heights.
接下來諷刺的是
The irony continues.
他和我媽被醉酒少年撞死...
When he and my mother were run over
by a drunken teenager...
在十年前的新年夜裡
on New Year's Eve
ten years ago...
他把最重要的...
he left the keys...
他的王國的東西...
to the kingdom...
留給了我
to me.
51%的股權
Fifty-one percent control.
其餘49%股權由七名董事共有...
Forty-nine percent going to a group
of seven board members...
他們每一個都認為自己是老大
who all thought they were
first in line.
而你認為是董事會...這7個矮人...
And you believe the board-
the Seven Dwarfs-
為了奪取公司控制權才陷害你入獄?
put you here to take control
of your company?
關你屁事?
What do you care?
我們只是聊天
We're just talking.
今晚是週三晚上...
And tonight's Wednesday night...
通常我要和兩個女兒去Black Angus吃晚飯
and I go to Black Angus for dinner
with my two daughters on Wednesdays.
所以我得快點走
So I'll have to leave soon.
你知道我們時間有限，對吧?
You do understand that our time
is limited, don't you?
如果我說出來...
If I talk...
你一定覺得我瘋了
you'll just think I'm crazy.
沒有不尊敬的意思, 想像有一個人...
With all the possible respect
I can offer a man...
戴著塑膠面具在大談陰謀論, 大衛...
wearing a latex mask and spouting
conspiracy theories, David...
相信我，你已經瘋了
believe me,
you've crossed that bridge.
祝你用餐愉快
Enjoy your dinner.
人生有五個最基本的情緒, 大衛
There are five basic emotions
in life, David.
告訴我，哪一種情緒在困擾著這個人...
Tell me,
what emotion gripped him...
在他進入牢房之前
before he entered that cell?
是罪惡感...
Was it guilt...
仇恨...
hate...
羞恥...
shame...
報復...
revenge...
愛?
love?
我完全猜錯了, 是吧?
I'm completely on the wrong track,
aren't I?
誰要冰塊?
Who needs ice?
大衛, 生日快樂
David, happy birthday.
你對鞋子的品味無人能及
You have got the greatest taste
in shoes, bar none anywhere.
- 艾瑪, 你見過利奈特了嗎?
- 沒, 但恐怕我倆沒共同點
- Emma, have you met Lynette?
- I fear what we may have in common.
大衛, 你邀請了整個奧林匹克雪板隊?
David, did you invite the entire
Olympic snowboarding team?
今晚是我生日
Tonight is my birthday.
- 對大衛說生日快樂
- 生日快樂
- Say happy birthday to David.
- Happy birthday.
歡迎來到聖地
Welcome to Graceland.
生日快樂, 臭小子
Happy birthday,
you son of a bitch.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
嗨, 各位朋友, 大家好
Hey, friends of me, hello.
- 玩瘋一點
- 立體影像就要開始了
- Let the fun ensue.
- Living Stereo will be on-line soon.
是偉大的約翰柯川(薩克斯演奏)
他們會喜歡登上雜誌的
It is the great John Coltrane.
They would love an article on it.
如果你喜歡,這是個很棒的原型
If you like it,
it's an amazing prototype.
- 別,別
- 不好意思
- 沒事
- Excuse me.
- No, no. Thank you. That's okay.
- 文學天才, 布萊恩謝比
- 生日快樂
- Literary god, Brian Shelby.
- Happy birthday.
還是那些相互間老套的話...
And all the usual shit
people say to each other-
- 你好嗎?
- 活在夢中, 寶貝, 活在夢中
- How you doing?
- Living the dream, baby, Living the dream.
大衛.埃姆斯
David Aames.
- 我如何能享受這份厚禮?
- 這禮物可是我索菲亞.塞拉諾的
- To what do I owe this pleasure?
- The pleasure of Sofia Serrano.
我今天在圖書館認識她, 你無法想像
We met today at the library,
if you can believe that.
抱歉, 我的外套對你的衣櫥來說太大了
Sorry about my coat.
It's too big for your closet.
- 我們假裝是知識份子
- 真不可思議, 我喜歡你的外套
- We were pretending to be intellectuals.
- It's amazing. I love your coat.
我穿得太講究了,我意思是,太糟了
I overdressed.
I mean, I underdressed.
我會假裝你們在聽我說
I'll continue like you're both
actually listening to me.
你還有其他地方放嗎?
Do you have another room
to put it in?
丹妮爾
Danielle.
我都不存在了
I have ceased to exist.
麥迪森廣場花園就在附近, 那裡也許夠大
Madison Square Garden is nearby.
It might fit there.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
- 我們一起挑的
- 謝謝你
- We picked it out together.
- Thank you.
我們..挑的..一起
We picked it out together.
- 我們
- 別客氣
- We.
- You're welcome.
別含情脈脈了, 拆禮物吧
Stop flirting and open it.
- 我們去喝一杯
- 是
- Let's get a drink.
- Yes.
我要拿到樓上
I'll leave this upstairs.
布萊恩, 過來...
Brian, come here...
- 我馬上回來
- 好的
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- 聽著
- 嘿, 湯米
- Listen.
- Hey, Tommy.
不, 不, 別把我甩了
No, no, don't blow me off.
我都打包好了, 我準備回倫敦了, 我也知道...
I'm all packed. I'm going
back to London and I understand.
你讓我做另外的律師工作, 這樣就不用開除我
You put me up for the other attorney's
job so you didn't have to fire me.
這很高明, 你老爸也會這麼做
That's a classy move and your father
would have done the same.
沒關係, 湯米
It's okay, Tommy.
我越來越不稱職了
I became incompetent.
沒什麼比一個老古董更沒用的了
Is there anything more unbecoming
than an aging mascot?
我關心你老爸
I cared for your father.
對他忠心耿耿
I lived and breathed for him.
那些傢夥, 那7個矮人...
These guys, the Seven Dwarfs...
他們覺得你很幼稚
they think you're stupid-
是公司的絆腳石, 是搗亂的人
a corporate hazard,
a rogue.
他們正想辦法把你趕走, 大衛
They are gonna find a way
to get you out, David.
他們會逐步奪走你的公司, 你的生活...
They're lined up for your office,
your life...
你的地位
your position.
他們處心積慮...
They're working day and night...
想搶走你51%的股權
to cheat you out
of your 51 % vote.
他們想賣掉這個文學的基業...
And they're gonna sell
this tradition of words...
這樣他們就可以為所欲為
so they can eat
in a better cafeteria.
但他們不知道的是
But what they don't know is this.
人們還會閱讀的!
People will read again!
我知道了
I got it.
他們甚至在你背後給你取外號
They even got a nickname for you
behind your back.
國民老二
Citizen Dildo.
你有了不起的天性...
You got great instincts...
但我要很誠摯的告訴你...
but I say this with complete love.
掌控你的人生...
Claim your life...
學會做一個混蛋
learn to be an asshole-
再說就多了
Two's enough.
對不起
Forgive me.
我對這家族仍有信心, 大衛...
I still believe
in this family, David...
雖然只剩下你
even if it's only you.
送提普離開這裡
Get Tipp out of here.
帶他回家, 然後明早...
Drive him home,
and in the morning...
告訴他被重新雇傭, 加薪50%
tell him he's rehired
with a 50% raise.
給他個大辦公室, 就在7矮人的對面
Give him that big office across
the hall from the Seven Dwarfs.
再安排和律師團的一個會議
And set up a meeting
with the other attorneys.
我明天會早一點
I'm gonna be in early tomorrow.
比平常早
Well, earlier than usual.
你好, 帥哥
Hello, handsome.
我來祝你生日快樂
I've come to wish you
a happy birthday.
噢, 天哪
Oh, man.
我沒邀請你, 茱莉
I didn't invite you,Julie.
- 這真有點奇怪
- 派對就是這樣
- That was a little weird.
- That's how it works with parties-
你得要被邀請
you have to be invited.
我在生你氣, 爛人
I'm mad at you, you dick.
那晚我們做了四次
We made love four times
the other night.
- 很棒嗎?
- 二次很棒
- Is that good?
- Two's good.
三次非常棒
Three is very good.
- 但四次...
- 四次超級棒?
- But four-
- Four's pretty good?
四次...
Four is-
四次怎樣?
Four is what?
抱抱我, 然後我就走
Hold me, and then I'll leave.
你就可以回去找那個可愛的褐發美女聊天
And you can go back and talk
to that cute brunette.
四次怎樣?
Four is what?
我不想見你那些高貴的朋友, 我以前也高貴的時候就知道他們
I don't wanna meet your fancy friends.
I knew them when I was fancy too.
四次怎樣?
Four is what?
她看起來像只飛蛾, 大衛
She looks like a moth, David.
飛蛾?
A moth?
有時候我真擔心你, 那些聰明的女孩...
Sometimes I worry about you,
that some clever girl...
穿著愚蠢的大衣就這麼出現, 把你耍得團團轉
in a big silly coat is gonna come
along and play you just right.
然後我就會失去我的朋友
Then I'll lose my friend.
我們就再沒有熬雞湯的聚會了
And there won't be any chicken soup
parties for me and you.
好吧
Okay.
壞人
Bad.
幾時再打給我? 別說"很快"
When will you call me?
Don't say "soon."
我討厭你說"很快"
I hate it when you say "soon."
丹尼布拉姆森在去年生日給他的
Danny Bramson gave him that
for his birthday last year.
這就是搖滾樂的下場...
So this is what's become
of rock and roll-
一把砸碎的吉它掛在有錢人家裡的玻璃櫃裡
a smashed guitar behind a glass case
displayed on some rich guy's wall.
這是個禮物, 實際上
It was a gift, actually.
- 我喜歡
- 喔, 喔, 喔
- I like it.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
你怎麼會有所有這些東西...
So how did you
get all this stuff-
這樣的公寓, 這樣的生活?
this apartment, this life?
我明白了
I see.
幫我一下怎樣, 沒打擾你的話
How 'bout if you help me,
unless I'm horning in here.
- 你的確打擾了, 但食物很好
- 我有麻煩, 有個人在暗戀我
- You are, but the food's good.
- I have a problem. I got a stalker.
聽起來生活不會變糟
It doesn't sound life threatening.
我想你假裝我們正在愉快的交談...
I need for you to pretend we are
having a scintillating conversation...
而你感到非常享受
and you are wildly entertained.
- 我知道這很難辦
- 我會配合的
- I know it's tough.
- I'll improvise.
她在屋子另一邊正盯我的背看, 是嗎?
She's across the room and burning
a hole in my back now, isn't she?
紅禮服, 系帶鞋?
Red dress, strappy shoes?
哇, 她真的在盯著你
Wow. She's really staring at you.
- 該死
- 她看起來快哭了
- Shit.
- And she seems to be crying.
很不開心
Less happy.
我想她是最傷心的女孩, 一直拿著杯馬提尼
I think she's the saddest girl
to ever hold a martini.
布萊恩.謝比
Brian Shelby.
- 珍妮佛.凱利
- 嗨, 珍妮佛
- Jennifer Kelly.
- Hi,Jennifer.
- 你還有另一個公寓
- 算是辦公室, 來吧
- You have another apartment.
- Sort of a day office. Come on.
- 我不要進去
- 好吧, 晚安
- I am not going in there.
- I am. Good night.
- 我聽到她來了
- 真的?
- I hear her coming.
- Really?
假的
No.
布萊恩
Brian.
- 嗨
- 你好嗎?
- Hi.
- How are you?
我們安全了, 但我沒東西喝
We're safe, but I've got
nothing to drink.
這些是誰畫的?
Who did these paintings?
這是瓊尼.蜜雪兒
This is Joni Mitchell.
這個是莫內
This one is Monet.
這一個是...
And this one...
我做的
was done by me.
是個雪板
It is a snowboard.
那麼, 只有兩個是天才
Well, two of them are geniuses.
那是真跡
That is the real thing.
他用畫筆描繪了這片香草的天空
His paintbrush painted
the vanilla sky.
這是...帆布的
And his canvas.
是我母親的
My mother's.
- 我很好奇你會感到意外
- 我真無話可說了
- I'm surprised you're surprised.
- I can't keep this banter going.
- 我也是
- 逮到你們了
- Me neither.
- I caught you.
布萊恩, 來這兒
Brian, come in here.
- 怎麼樣?
- 你的朋友很有意思, 我也醉了
- What's going on?
- Your friends are fun and I'm drunk.
- 茱莉吉雅妮在跟蹤我
- 她看起來很危險
- Julie Gianni is stalking me.
- She looked dangerous.
沒人跟蹤我, 我只好喝酒
Nobody stalks me,
so I drink.
- 這都沒酒了
- 喝我的傑克丹尼(威士卡)加可樂吧
- We're all out up here.
- Finish my Jack and Coke.
- 愚蠢的玻璃杯
- 我來
- Stupid glass.
- I got it.
- 不, 是拿著它的人蠢
- 別擔心, 沒什麼大不了的
- No. It's the stupid guy holding it.
- Don't worry. No big deal.
我去弄些東西來, 傑克加可樂?
I'll go get us something.
Jacks and Cokes?
我最好識相點,我喝太多了,還他媽的沒吃東西
I better hit it. I drank
too much and I didn't fuckin' eat.
- 派對才剛開始
- 對你而言
- The party's just starting.
- For you it is.
你不能走, 你是我的貴賓
You cannot go.
You are my guest of honor.
去你的, 大衛
Fuck you, David.
你給我錢寫小說, 你是老大
You're paying me to write my novel,
so you own me.
我不是,你才華橫溢,又好看,又瀟灑
I don't own you. You are brilliant,
good-looking, handsome.
但你為什麼非得勾引索菲亞?
But why'd you have to hit
on Sofia?
- 我沒勾引她
- 算了, 隨你怎麼說
- I wasn't hitting on Sofia.
- Fine. Whatever you say.
- 我瘋了, 我瞎了眼
- 你沒有
- I'm crazy. I'm blind.
- You're not blind.
你喝了傑克丹尼, 當你喝了傑克你就會開始變成...
You're drinking Jack Daniels and when
you drink jack you start in with that...
弗蘭克.辛納屈(音樂人)-- 她傷了我的心...
Frank Sinatra,
she shot me down...
給我根香煙. 最傷心的人
give me a cigarette
king of sad thing.
- 沒錯, 給我根香煙
- 我去找根
- That I do. Give me a cigarette.
- I'll find one.
等等,你很有錢女人都愛你,而我是來自俄亥俄的(意指鄉巴佬)醉鬼
Wait. You're rich and women love
you and I'm from Ohio and drunk.
- 我可以告訴你實話嗎?
- 任何人都可以
- Can I tell you the truth?
- Everybody does.
我喜歡她
I dig her.
之前我從沒和你提過這個,包括任何女孩...
And I've never said this to you
before about any girl...
但她很可能...很可能...很可能就是
but she could be-
could be- could be-
就是我那個他媽的夢中女孩
could be the girl
of my fucking dreams.
- 你不是鄉下來的
- 我知道
- You're not from Ohio.
- I know.
但如果她會毀了我們的友誼, 那她可以去死了
But if she fucks up our friendship,
she can go to hell.
我不允許這種情況發生, 我們是哥們
I won't allow it.
We are bros.
- 我也是這麼覺得
- 你當然是
- I feel the same way.
- Sure you do.
- 嗨
- 你好嗎?
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- 謝謝
- 別客氣
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
我是弗蘭克(電燈泡),弗蘭克必須走
I am Frank,
and Frank must go.
- 什麼?
- 我祝你們今晚愉快
- What?
- I good you bid evening.
等等, 我和你一起走
Wait. I'll go with you.
- 留下來, 親愛的
- 晚點我會載你回家的
- Stay, baby.
- I'll give you a ride home later.
- 不, 明天我得上班
- 你...
- No, I have to work tomorrow.
- You-
你會得到很好的照顧的
You are in great hands.
我的話只是為了安慰自己
I'm just humoring myself
that my opinion matters.
你永遠體會不到那種深深的痛苦...
You will never know
the exquisite pain...
一個人獨自回家...
of the guy who goes home alone...
因為沒有這痛苦, 親愛的, 那就無所謂甜蜜
because without the bitter, baby,
the sweet ain't as sweet.
玩的愉快
Have a good time.
又是這套心酸和甜蜜
The sweet and sour speech again.
- 為什麼你有懼高症?
- 很多人都有
- Why are you scared of heights?
- Many people are scared of heights.
我不是怕高, 而是感到困擾
It's not the height
that bothers me.
是那種壓力在威脅著我
It's the impact
that terrifies me.
我不會待太久
I won't stay long.
嘿, 保羅
Hey, Paolo.
你好
Hello.
我得帶你去散步
I have to take you for a walk.
幸好有它保護著你, 它是個猛犬
I'm glad he protects you.
He's a lethal canine.
我喜歡住這裡, 我也懶得打掃
I love living here,
and I refuse to clean up.
沒事
No problem.
我得拼命打工才住的起這裡
I have to work around the clock
to keep this place.
- 你真的是個舞蹈家
- 十四年了
- You really are a dancer.
- For 14 years.
但我可不會跳得像你那樣
But I don't dance like you dance.
想喝什麼嗎?
Do you want something to drink?
好的
Sure.
嘿, 真乖, 乖孩子
Hey, beautiful, beautiful boy.
晚餐想吃什麼?
What do you want
for dinner tonight?
想吃炸雞嗎?
Do you want fried chicken?
我喜歡你的生活
I like your life.
好吧, 這是我的, 你不能擁有它
Well, it's mine
and you can't have it.
我不想知道這照片背後的故事
I don't wanna know the story
behind this photo.
- 誰是塞爾吉奧?
- 這是個綽號
- Who's Sergio?
- It's a nickname.
- 你外號叫塞爾吉奧?
- 說來話長
- Your nickname is Sergio?
- It's a long story.
我們互相都還不熟
And we don't know each other.
- 這麼多秘密啊
- 因為我是個軍火商(在調侃大衛的姓氏)
- So many secrets.
- That's because I'm an arms dealer.
- 我從沒認識過軍火商
- 現在認識了
- I've never known an arms dealer.
- You do now.
那你呢?
你的綽號是什麼?
What about you?
What's your nickname?
國民老二
Citizen Dildo.
你不能在這呆一晚上
You are not staying over.
別做老闆, 做個藝術家, 或者軍火商
Never run a company. Stay an artist.
Stay an arms dealer.
拜託, 不知為何我無法同情你
Oh, please. Somehow
I can't play the violin for you.
雖然, 能影響那麼多人的生活一定很困難
Although, it must be difficult
controlling all those people's lives.
派對上每個和你有聯繫的人某種程度上都靠你吃飯
Everyone at that party is connected
to you for survival in some way.
看起來
It seems.
結過婚嗎?
Ever been married?
沒有,你曾經接受過一萬兩千個男人的求婚?
Did you ever accept any
of your 12,000 proposals?
一萬兩千零八個. 沒有
Twelve thousand and eight. No.
然後你搬到紐約來跳舞,畫畫, 表演和賣軍火?
And you moved to New York to dance,
paint, act and deal arms?
是的
Right.
你想聽傑夫.巴克利還是維姬.卡爾?
Do you wanna hear Jeff Buckley
or Vicki Carr?
傑夫.巴克利還是維姬.卡爾?
Jeff Buckley or Vicki Carr?
一起聽
Both simultaneously.
每個人都說,"別到紐約"
Everyone said,
"Don't go to New York."
我只是覺得好事總會發生...
I just think good things
will happen...
如果你是好人有好的心態的話
if you're a good person
with a good attitude.
你不覺得嗎?
Don't you think?
你覺得我很天真嗎?
You think I'm naive?
不, 絕對沒有
No. I really don't.
我真的喜歡上她了
I dug her completely.
忽然間...我發現了紐約最後一個單純的女孩
Somehow I'd found the last
semi-guyless girl in New York City.
我得睡覺了
I have to get to sleep.
說實話, 白天我還有個工作是牙醫助理
Truthfully, I also work mornings
as a dental assistant.
天哪, 我都找錯牙醫了
Boy, am I going
to the wrong dentist.
而你都沒有馬上就想和她上床?
And you didn't immediately
wanna sleep with her?
額, 你知道, 我是個延遲享樂者
Well, you know,
I'm a pleasure delayer.
- 那是什麼意思?
- 延遲享樂者?
- How does that work?
- Pleasure delayer?
你不知道?
You don't know?
你保持和一個人順其自然的交往...
You keep a relationship casual...
直到一個絕佳的機會
until the absolute breaking point.
然後在一個晚上..或中午...或早上...
And then one evening
or afternoon or morning-
那得花上好幾個月
it could be months from now.
你知道這是怎麼一回事
You know how it works.
不, 說實話不知道
No, actually I don't.
我結婚22年了
I've been married for 22 years.
你還要和女兒吃飯
You've got dinner
with your daughters.
沒錯, 我知道
That's right, I do.
那時我有各種招數對付女人...
Back then I had intricate systems
with women...
你不會相信
you wouldn't believe.
比如?
Like what?
嘿, 醫生, 別再為不是單身而難過了...
Hey, Doc, don't get melancholy over
the 30 seconds you were single...
很久以前的了
a long time ago.
- 你覺得我是這樣嗎?
- 是的
- That's what you think I'm doing?
- Oh, yes.
你也許是對的
You might be right.
我們繼續吧, 時間不等人
Let's continue.
Time is not our friend.
只限於缺點, 我們只能畫這些
Just our shortcomings,
that's all we're allowed to draw.
我從來沒畫得這麼像過
I've never drawn such
a true likeness before.
我畫好了
Mine's finished.
這麼快?
Already?
好了
Done.
- 你是這麼看我的嗎?
- 也許錢畫得還不夠多
- That's how you see me?
- Maybe I didn't add enough money.
不, 你簡直畫得入木三分
No, something you'd see on a wall
in a steak house in hell.
太棒了, 簽名吧
It's wonderful.
Sign it.
讓我看你的
Let's see yours.
不
No.
把它給我
Give me that.
我很內疚
I feel bad.
你說要畫滑稽的
You said to draw a caricature.
我知道, 但沒辦法
I know. I couldn't.
我看見你就是這樣的
I saw you like that.
畫得很好
It's very good.
我要賣給你
I'll sell it to you.
你這壞人
You monster.
這多少錢?
How much for it?
一個吻
One kiss.
這笑容太令我陶醉了
That smile is gonna be
the end of me.
明天你朋友打給你怎麼辦?
And what happens when
your friend calls you tomorrow?
他只比我早遇見你幾個鐘頭, 他也會這麼做的
He just met you a few hours
before me. He'd do the same.
我覺得友情對你很重要
I see that friendship
is important to you.
沒錯, 是的
It is. It is.
我是他最好的朋友...
And as his best friend...
我知道他正準備完成一部關於缺憾和拒絕的小說
I know he's trying to finish a novel
about inadequacy and rejection.
所以我在這呆的越久,對他的前途就越好
So the longer that I stay,
the better it is for his career.
你的前途才是我擔心的
Your career is the one
I'd worry about.
對不起
Sorry.
不, 不, 其實你說得沒錯
No. No, you're more right
than you even know.
我曾經是那種傢夥...
I used to be one of those guys
that just...
雪板就是他的生活...
snowboarded through his life...
沒有目標...
with no focus...
完全沒有
whatsoever.
你幾時改變的?
When did you change?
大概五分鐘前
About five minutes ago.
每一分鐘都有可能會改變你的生活
Every passing minute is another
chance to turn it all around.
對於那些認為你是個騙子的人?
And to those who think
that you're a charlatan?
我知道
I understand.
這種觀點是把人冷凍起來...
The perception of a head
frozen somewhere...
等待復蘇, 聽起來像科幻小說
waiting for reanimation
sounds like science fiction.
- 你在看什麼?
- 最棒的節目
- What are you watching?
- It's the greatest show.
叫做索菲亞
It's called Sofia.
這是新科技的最前沿
It is at the frontier
of a new science.
生命延續
Life Extension.
你如何實現這樣的構想呢?
How do you accomplish
such a thing?
我看過這個30遍了
I've seen this 30 times.
生命充滿了意外
Life is full of surprises.
但最大的意外就是生命不是非得終結
But the greatest surprise of all is
that this doesn't have to end ever.
我們報導過他, 他擁有半個亞利桑那州
We did a story on this guy.
He owns half of Arizona.
- 他是騙子嗎?
- 誰知道呢?
- Is he a fraud?
- How would you ever know?
說得好
Good point.
你能把人解凍嗎?
Can you unfreeze a human life?
以小狗班尼為例, 班尼是只小狗
Take the case of Benny the dog.
Benny's a dog.
它被冷凍了三個月然後被解凍了, 過上正常的生活
He was frozen for three months and
thawed out to live a normal life.
令人欣慰嗎?
That's comforting?
班尼沒事了
我也要生命延續
It's safe for Benny.
I'm in.
我們最好慢慢來
We'd better watch out.
雷蒙德.圖利,生命延續的創始人
Raymond Tooley,
creator of Life Extension.
書名是 生命:續集
The book is Life: The Sequel.
- 你要去哪?
- 我留了號碼在你冰箱上
- Where are you going?
- I left my number on your fridge.
過來, 我想告訴你個秘密
Come here.
I want to tell you a secret.
我本來是要親你的額頭
I meant that to be your forehead.
謝謝你心有靈犀
Thank you for the inspiration.
現在我要嘗試以仁慈之心去經營我的公司...
I will now attempt to run
my company showing compassion...
接納我那幾個搭檔的抱怨...
for the seething throng
of my partners...
他們誠心想把我搞垮...
who root quietly for me to fail.
還有那些背地裡你不知道的東西
And for things you don't even know.
謝謝
Thank you.
我要去上班了, 我還有間公司要經營呢
I'm gonna go to work.
I have a company to run.
延遲享樂者
Pleasure delayer.
大衛.埃姆斯
David Aames.
茱莉.吉雅妮
Julie Gianni.
嘿, 帥哥
Hey, handsome.
你在跟蹤我
You're following me.
有點算是吧
Just a little bit.
我想完成我們那天的對話
I wanted to finish
what we were talking about.
然後呢?
And?
和我們的飛蛾女孩相處得怎樣了? 她有為你蛻變成蝴蝶嗎?
How did it go with our moth girl?
She turn into a butterfly for you?
是的, 她有
Yes, she did.
她有
She did.
看得出來就憑你走路的樣子, 你沒和她上床
I can tell by the way you were
walking you didn't sleep with her.
讓我猜猜, 你沒和她上床是因為...
Let me guess. You haven't slept
with her because...
越是觸手可及就越刺激
it's more fun
when you can draw it out.
性會變得沒意思, 如果一個女人不再告訴她的朋友...
Sex just isn't as good if a woman
hasn't told her friends...
她從來沒和你上過床的話
she'd never sleep with you.
非常正確, 茱莉
Right on the money,Julie.
她一定整晚想你想到發瘋
She must be exhausted from trying
to be witty for you all night.
嘿, 茱莉
Hey,Julie.
對不起
Sorry.
沒事
It's okay.
你似乎從來都不會珍惜直到快要失去朋友
You never seem to be there for your
friends until they've given up on you.
我沒有不理你, 我只是...
I'm not blowing you off.
I just-
我有點想一個人靜靜, 相信我
I wanna be alone
for a little bit. Trust me.
我有很多事, 必須要處理
I have a lot of things
I have to take care of.
如果我們是朋友, 我們的確是...
And if we're friends,
which we are...
對吧, 那麼你應該會理解
okay, then
you'll understand that.
對不起, 我有點怪怪的
I'm sorry.
I got weird.
我錯過了試鏡, 而且...
I missed an audition and...
那讓我很難過,你沒有邀請我參加派對
it just made me feel bad you
didn't invite me to your party.
你要補償我嗎?
You wanna make it up to me?
我不會告訴別人的
I won't tell a soul.
你會報導我嗎,如果我出了一張唱片?
Would you do a story on me
if I made a CD?
當然我會的
Sure I would.
你喜歡我的音樂嗎?
Do you like my music?
很有活力
It's vivid.
要是我的話我也會買一張給自己
Well, if I weren't me,
I would buy a CD by me.
你知道, 只要有一個人欣賞你...
Well, you know,
if you can reach one person-
哇
Wow.
幸福對你來說是什麼, 大衛?
What's happiness to you, David?
幸福對我來說?
What's happiness to me?
- 幸福是什麼...
- 對我來說...
- What is happiness-
- 'Cause for me...
這就是幸福
this is happiness-
就是和你在一起
just being with you.
就是有一件事很困擾我
There's one thing
that bothers me.
為什麼你和布萊恩說我是你的炮友?
Why did you tell Brian
that I was your fuck buddy?
我沒告訴他, 我沒那麼說過
I didn't tell him that.
I didn't say that.
- 你什麼時候不再關心了, 大衛?
- 關心什麼?
- When did you stop caring, David?
- Caring about what?
那些你許下的承諾的後果
About the consequences of
the promises that you've made.
- 承諾?
- 是的, 承諾
- Promises?
- Yeah, the promises.
我以為...
I thought-
操啊, 你在說什麼啊?
Get the fuck-
What are you talking about?
你知道假裝是你好友有多難嗎?
Do you understand how hard it is
to pretend to be your buddy?
大衛, 我愛你
David, I love you.
我他媽的愛你!
I fucking love you!
操!
Fuck!
哇, 哇, 哇!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
別這樣, 別這樣
Don't do this.
那晚我們做了四次
You fucked me four times
the other night.
你進入我的身體
You've been inside me.
我為你口交, 那是有意義的
I swallowed your cum.
That means something.
開慢點
Slow down.
四次, 那是有意義的
Four times- it means something.
- 四次
- 停車
- Four times.
- Stop the car.
每天, 我過著期盼的生活...
Twenty-four hours a day, I live
with this aching possibility...
你也許會打電話叫我去做些什麼
that you might call me
to do something.
我們去你家吧, 我想看你住的地方
Let's go to your house.
I wanna see where you live.
快開慢點, 我要你停車!
Just slow down.
I want you to stop the car!
你知道當你和一個人上床...
Don't you know when you sleep
with someone...
你的身體就許下了承諾, 不管你想不想
your body makes a promise
whether you do or not?
告訴我, 大衛, 你信上帝嗎?
Tell me something, David.
Do you believe in God?
你要做什麼?
What are you doing?
好吧, 我愛你, 我愛你
Okay, I love you.
I love you.
別亂來!
Don't do it!
你好
hello.
你真美
You're amazing.
- Hola
- Hola.
你已經沒事去上班了?
Did you get to work all right?
不, 實際上, 我做了一場噩夢
No, actually,
I had a horrible dream.
夢見你再也見不到我了
You dreamed you'd never
see me again.
我離開了你的公寓之後, 下樓去取車...
I left your apartment,
I went downstairs to the car...
然後我的朋友, 那個暗戀者, 跟蹤我到那
and my friend, the stalker,
had followed me there.
茱莉
Julie.
是的, 然後她想和我談談
Yes. And she wanted
to talk to me.
但我記得我腦子裡都是那些細語, 你知道...
And I remember I had this buzz,
you know...
那是來自我們的交談
that buzz from you and me.
我想我的意識還停留在我那幅滑稽的肖像上
I think my mind was still on
that terrible drawing of me.
但她覺得很心煩...
But she was upset...
嗯...是關於...我不知道
about- I don't know.
我上了她的車然後...
I got in the car and...
她開車沖到橋下...
she drove off a bridge...
連我帶車一起自殺
and committed suicide
with me in the car.
我以為你直接就去上班了
I thought you were going
straight to work.
但我活了下來...
But I survived...
我的臉和手都...
with my arm and my face...
毀了
reconstructed.
更糟的是...
And what's worse...
我沒法醒過來
is that I can't wake up.
你家裡怎樣了...派對之後
And how was your house
after the party?
派對?
Party?
什麼派對?
What party?
就是那個派對啊
The party.
記得嗎?
Remember?
紅禮服, 系帶鞋
Red dress, strappy shoes.
我把東西灑在你的襯衫上
I spilled something
on your shirt.
甜蜜和心酸
Sweet and sour.
一直拿著馬提尼的傷心女孩
And the saddest girl
to ever hold a martini.
我的夢是一個殘酷的玩笑
My dreams are a cruel joke.
它們嘲諷我
They taunt me.
即使在夢裡, 我也是個傻瓜...
Even in my dreams,
I'm an idiot...
知道自己就快要醒來面對現實
who knows he's about
to wake up to reality.
如果我可以不睡的話...
If I could only avoid sleep.
但我做不到
But I can't.
我試著告訴自己做其他的夢
I try to tell myself
what to dream.
我嘗試夢到自己在飛
I try to dream that I'm flying.
做些自由的事
Something free.
但沒有用
It never works.
那就是你唯一夢到的事?
Is that the only thing you dream?
我不...不記得了
I don't- I don't remember.
你夢到那場車禍了嗎?
Do you dream about
the car accident?
這就是你在昏迷中的記憶...
Here's what you remember
from a coma.
...一片空白
Nothing.
接下來發生了什麼?
What happened next?
到底發生了什麼?
What really happened?
什麼, 你沒看檔案嗎?
What, didn't you read
the file?
我昏迷了三個半星期
I was out for
three-and-a-half weeks.
我的臉和手臂都破碎了, 下頜有四處骨折
My face and my arm shattered and
my jaw was broken in four places.
因為昏迷無法實施外科手術
No surgery could be performed
because of the coma.
你無法體會那種黑暗...
You can't feel the darkness...
還有麻木
or numbness.
你甚至毫無知覺
You can't even feel.
然後...
And then...
我又回到我的生活
I came back to life.
就像小狗班尼
Just like that dog.
班尼, 你知道, 那只小狗
Benny. You know, Benny the dog.
班尼, 小狗班尼
Benny. Benny the dog.
只是我的生活不再正常
Only my life
was no longer normal.
神經損傷讓我頭痛欲裂
There are blinding migraines now-
nerve damage.
為什麼?
Why?
這就和大企業操縱...
This is how
big business operates-
隨機的意外一樣
random accidents...
一個生活中的事故
a lifestyle mishap.
這都不是巧合
They are not coincidences.
你不覺得再縝密的合同都會有破綻嗎?
How do you think
airtight contracts are broken?
這都是因為權利的爭奪
These are power upheavals.
我是從鄉下來的
I'm from Ohio.
我們沒見過權利爭奪
We don't have power upheavals.
每天的新聞都有, 就在字裡行間
They are in the news every day
right between the lines.
有人故意這樣對我
Someone did this to me.
我爸在他的書裡就寫過這些
My father wrote about this
in his book.
第一章, 第一頁...
Chapter one, page one...
第一段
paragraph one-
"一百個問題中有九十九個答案是什麼?
"What is the answer to 99
out of 100 questions?
錢."
Money."
大衛, 聽著, 我不想讓你擔心
David, look,
I don't wanna worry you.
我正在應付, 但現在有個情況
I'm holding them off,
but we got a situation here.
根據董事會的規章, 要保有你51%的股權...
The bylaws of the board
protect your 51 % vote...
你必須心智正常
only if you're mentally acute.
我很遺憾那可憐的女孩死了...
I'm sorry that poor girl died...
但你還掌握著董事會, 真是不幸中的萬幸
but you've handed the board
a real gift with your mishap.
他們想宣佈你讓權
They'd like to declare you
incapacitated.
但你又回來了
But you're back.
聽到你的聲音真好, 就讓我們和那幫混蛋開戰吧...
You sound good to me,
so let's fight the fuckers...
好好養傷
and have a full recovery.
也許你應該讓大家見見你?
And maybe you should let
people see you, yeah?
上次我們一起去, 你還在昏迷...
The last time we were together
you were in a coma...
你對我真他媽的沒禮貌
and you were very
fucking rude to me.
你都沒說一句話
You didn't say a word.
是的, 關於我去世的謠言被有些誇大了
Yes, well, the rumors of my death
have been mildly exaggerated.
我該相信誰?
Who could I trust?
螞蟻們都在蟻丘上議論紛紛呢
The ants were taking over
the anthill.
我該相信誰?
Who could I trust?
頭骨打了30顆鋼釘...
The cranial structure
was based on 30 pins...
並用下頜骨碎片固定
and fastened by micro-panels
and bits of bone from the mandible.
看起來軟骨成型技術保持了你的臉部結構
It appears the cartilage graphs
have maintained your cheek structure.
不幸的是, 由於你一直昏迷...
Unfortunately,
because you were in a coma-
醫生, 他們滿口術語, 那你只好做些功課...
Doctors. Their power is in jargon,
so you study up.
這過程造成的雙側眶周血腫...
Is that the procedure for all
bilateral periorbital hematomas...
是由於昏迷患者的勒福氏骨折嗎
in a LeFort Three fracture
of a comatose patient?
- 勒福氏骨折?
- ...你做到最好
- In a LeFort Three?
- You do your best.
當然
Absolutely.
顱內腦損傷的機率太大了
The potential for intracranial
brain damage was too great.
除了面部移植, 波梅蘭茲醫生...
Beyond the cheek grafts,
Dr. Pomeranz...
是否用那些鋼釘固定...
are the pins fastened with any kind
of aluminum which could ionize...
會在我腦袋裡造成壓力?
and cause that pressure
in my head?
- 我已準備接受手術
- 我們正在研究
- I'm ready for another operation.
- We are working on processes.
但你並不適合做手術, 我們還在實驗
But you're specifically not at
the stage where we can experiment.
實驗, 就用我吧
Experiment. Use me.
頭痛將會消失
The headaches will go away.
這不只是頭痛
These are more than headaches.
這就像用鋼板切斷了我所有的思想
These are like steel plates
slicing through my every thought.
我們不是牛仔, 不會這樣隨意就做
We're not cowboys.
We can't just wing it.
大部分時間我都無法認真思考
Because I can't think straight
most of the time.
- 我們可以增加你的藥量
- 噢, 是啊, 藥物
- We can increase your medication.
- Oh, yes, medication.
我們會繼續研究方案
And there are things
that we'll continue to investigate.
不管怎樣, 有很多人都沒有這種效果...
However, there are so many others
who've not had the aesthetic benefit...
像你整形出來這樣
of plastic surgery
as you have.
這無關虛榮, 波梅蘭茲醫生
This isn't about vanity,
Dr. Pomeranz.
這無關虛榮
This isn't about vanity.
這是關於正常的功能
This is about functioning
in the world.
完整的功能是我正常運作必須的
It's my job to be out there
functioning.
我有錢, 我會出任意價格
I've got the money.
I'll pay any amount.
發明些什麼吧
Just invent something.
發揮想像力
Just play jazz.
你們自稱是紐約最好的整形醫生
You say you're
the best face man in New York.
他媽的證明給我看
Fucking prove it.
- 我們可以給你的手臂做手術
- 去他媽的手臂!
- We could do something about your arm.
- Fuck my arm!
這兒沒人自以為能體會到你的感受
Nobody here takes your feelings
for granted.
根據初步的診斷我們的確為你準備了一樣東西
We did prepare something for you
based on the preliminary examination.
說吧, 拿出來
Tell me. Bring it on.
這在排斥反應的初期是很有用的
It's sometimes useful
in the early stages of rejection.
是一個面部假體, 花了兩周才做好
It's a facial prosthetic.
It was two weeks in the making.
- 謝謝, 卡莉
- 不客氣, 醫生
- Thank you, Carly.
- You're welcome, Doctor.
一個面部假體
A facial prosthetic.
作為外觀的替代品它的確很有效...
The aesthetic replacement
does work...
無論心理上還是生理上
emotionally and actually.
面具上的塑膠還可以阻擋不良的射線...
The plastic in the aesthetic shield
also blocks out abusive rays...
有助於細胞的重生
and assists in
the regeneration of cells.
所以這是個外觀重建的護罩?
So it's an aesthetic
regenerative shield.
正確, 完全地
That's correct. Exactly.
護罩的人體工學原理還能使其自我調整...
The ergonomics of the plate barrier
allows it to interact reflexively...
與你的臉部動作緊密結合
with the movements
of your own face.
我知道了
I see.
- 這是個有用的東西
- 好
- It's a helpful unit.
- Good.
因為就這一會兒功夫裡, 我還以為我們只是在談論...
Because for a minute there,
I thought we were talking...
一個他媽的面具!
about a fucking mask!
這就只是個面具...
It's only a mask...
如果你這樣認為的話
if you treat it that way.
太棒了, 萬聖節真是派上用場了
It's great. This completely
takes care of Halloween.
但是其他那364天怎麼辦呢?
But what about the other
364 days of the year?
一個全新的我逐漸成形
A new form of me
began to take shape.
我計畫著我的複出...
I planned my reemergence...
就像諾曼地登陸
like the Normandy invasion.
索菲亞, 索菲亞
Sofia. Sofia.
索菲亞.塞拉諾
Sofia Serrano.
我只會說
I'll just say it.
我做足了功課
I did my homework.
我看了每一份備忘錄
I read every memo.
湯瑪斯.提普是對的
Thomas Tipp was right.
人們會再閱讀
People will read again.
我通過視頻參加每月和七個矮人的董事會議
I attended the monthly board meeting
with the Seven Dwarfs by video hookup.
因為人們不再買書了
Because people
aren't buying books.
- 讓我們投資吧
- 噢, 天哪, 這是戰爭
- Let's invest.
- Oh, baby, this was war.
我以這種方式變得越來越強, 我以前都不知道
I grew stronger in ways
I'd never known before.
然後到了十二月五日...
And on December 5...
我的飛機佈滿了天空...
my planes filled the sky.
大衛.埃姆斯的複出...
The return of David Aames, Jr...
國民老二2世
Citizen Dildo.
你不會相信這個...
You won't believe this...
但這是我的笑容
but this is me smiling.
好久不見
It's been a long time.
我想找你, 但你的人不讓我進去
I tried to see you,
but your people wouldn't let me.
我都不想見我, 好吧?
I didn't want to see me, okay?
但是後來...
But then...
今天我醒來, 發現...
I woke up today
and finally...
頭髮真好看
a good hair day.
你想和我約會嗎?
You wanna get together?
當然
Sure.
- 真的嗎?
- 讓我們出去做點什麼
- What?
- Let's go out and do something.
這週末
This weekend.
我要取消幾個常式
I'll cancel an operation or two.
我們會很開心...
We'll have fun...
因為我是個玩家
because I am all about fun.
好的, 觀眾們, 今晚第一個嘉賓是一個神奇的生存故事
Okay, folks, our first guest tonight
is an amazing survival story.
歡迎小狗班尼
Please welcome Benny the dog.
歡迎來上節目, 謝謝你來這裡
So welcome to the show.
Thank you very much for being here.
- 真的, 我很榮幸
- 我有很多問題
- You bet. My pleasure.
- I have so many questions.
首先, 和我們談談班尼發生了什麼事
To start off, tell us all
what has happened to Benny.
它經歷過什麼?
What's Benny been through?
好的, 班尼掉進了我家附近的河水裡
Well, Benny fell into the water
near our home.
然後它被凍在凱科米什河裡
And he was frozen
in the Skykomish River.
- 在華盛頓
- 沒錯
- In Washington.
- That's right.
我去釣魚, 正想著它已經失蹤三個月了
I went fishing, thinking he'd
been gone now for three months.
然後發現它在一個冰塊裡
And I see him
in a block of ice.
它現在已經被解凍了, 對嗎?
He is thawed out now.
Is that correct?
它不再活蹦亂跳了, 我很擔心
He's not moving a lot.
I'm worried.
我應該去拿個鉗子嗎? 我很擔心這小狗
Should I get out some tongs?
I'm worried about the dog.
不, 它沒事, 它只是少一些活潑
No, he's fine. He's just lost
a little bit of his friskiness.
我也這麼想
I would think so, yeah.
索菲亞, 我是大衛, 又來吵你了
It's David.
I'm back in your life.
今早我剛見過你
I saw you earlier today.
我正看到我們的老朋友小狗班尼...
I was just watching
our old friend Benny the dog...
在上節目...
on Conan...
然後我想到你
and I thought of you.
無所謂了
Whatever.
很高興今天見到你
I loved seeing you today.
我會很快再見你的
So I will see you soon.
你是個很棒的舞者
You're a great dancer.
再見
Bye.
- 你在喝什麼?
- 沒什麼
- What you drinkin'?
- Nothing.
我有意來一杯廉價的, 含糖的, 朗姆酒加可樂
I'm in the mood for a cheap,
sugary, overpriced rum and Coke.
- 你要嗎?
- 還有其他的?
- So you want one?
- Is there any other kind?
我去買
I'll get us some.
洗手間在哪?
Where is the bathroom?
就在那個地方的後面...
It's behind-
over there by the place...
那個看起來像比約克的女孩那邊
by the girl who looks like Bjork.
- 我就回來
- 也許我應該...
- I'll be right back.
- Maybe I should-
嘿, 老兄, 你看起來不錯, 你的書怎麼樣?
Hey, man, you look good.
How's your book?
- 脫下來
- 不, 這是個面罩
- Take it off.
- No, this is a facial shield.
這是個美觀的假體, 這些他媽的醫生...
It's an aesthetic prosthesis
these fucking doctors-
拿掉那面罩, 老兄, 它把我嚇壞了
Take off the mask, man.
It's freaking me out.
不行
I can't.
這是我的臉, 這就是我的臉
It's my face.
This is my face.
相信我, 那有點不一樣
Trust me.
It's a little different.
如果你覺得尷尬, 就走吧, 沒人要找你作伴
If you're embarrassed, just go.
Nobody asked you to chaperone.
- 索菲亞找我來的
- 什麼?
- Sofia asked me.
- What?
她不想獨自和我在一起? 真是胡扯!
She didn't want to be alone with me?
That's bullshit!
我覺得我都已經他媽的能接受這整件事了
Because I think I'm being pretty
fucking cool about this whole thing.
去和心理醫生說
Talk to a shrink.
或者有時間可以打給我, 而不是躲在你的公寓裡
Or you can call me sometime
instead of hiding in your apartment.
別對一個女孩子這樣, 你只見過她一次
Don't take it out on a girl
you only met once.
這是她說的嗎?
Did she say that-
一次?
once?
她說了我只見過她一次嗎?
Did she say
that I met her once?
打住, 好嗎?
Just cut it out, okay?
我懷念以前的你
I miss the old you.
我們都懷念以前的你...
We all miss the old you...
因為現在這個是個爛人
because the new guy is shit.
說錯了, 我愛你
That came out wrong.
I love you.
某段時期
Period.
- 你手臂怎麼樣, 老兄?
- 去你的, 布萊恩
- How's your arm, man?
- Fuck you, Brian.
要不這樣...
How 'bout...
不要同情
no sympathy.
要不這就是我們的約定, 好...嗎?
How 'bout that's
the deal we make, okay?
給我來杯百威和一小杯龍舌蘭
Give me a Budweiser
and a shot of tequila.
哪種龍舌蘭?
What kind of tequila?
- 你說什麼?
- 我說, 哪種龍舌蘭?
- What did you say to me?
- I said, what kind of tequila?
為什麼不看著我的臉說, 婊子?
Why don't you ask me
to my face, bitch?
培恩的, 如果你有的話
Patrón, if you have it.
再來杯龍舌蘭和百威
Another shot, another Bud.
- 這杯免費
- 為什麼?
- This is on the house.
- Why?
就這樣, 婊子
It just is, bitch.
培恩!
Patrón!
老兄, 整一下你他媽的臉
Dude, fix your fucking face.
- 又見面了
- Hello again.
我有個想法
Idea.
讓我們重新開始吧
Let's start over.
能幫我個忙嗎? 不打擾的話
How 'bout if you help me?
Unless I'm horning in here.
哦, 你擾到了, 不過食物不錯
Oh, you are,
but the food is good.
看, 我有個小麻煩, 有人跟蹤我
See, I've got this little problem.
I've got a stalker.
聽起來沒什麼大不了. 我需要個擋箭牌
Doesn't sound life-threatening.
I need a cover.
我需要你假裝我們在愉快的交談...
I need for you to pretend that we're
having a scintillating conversation...
而你非常享受
and you are wildly entertained.
我知道這很為難. 我會配合的
I know it's tough.
I'll improvise.
我不是那樣說的
I don't talk like that.
她就在屋子另一邊, 正盯著我背後看
She's right across the room.
She's burning a hole in my back now.
紅禮服, 系帶鞋
Red dress, strappy shoes.
沒錯
That's right.
我想她就是那個最傷心的女孩...
I think she is the saddest girl...
一直拿著一杯馬提尼
to ever hold a martini.
- 你還好吧?
- 不
- Are you okay?
- No.
為什麼? 怎麼了? 是我嗎?
Why? What's wrong?
Is it me?
- 是我嗎?
- 以後再說
- Is it me?
- I'll tell you later.
- 以後再說
- 不對勁, 拜託, 和我說啊
- I'll tell you later.
- Something's wrong. Please. Tell me now.
現在就說出來
Talk about it all right now.
- 快說, 全都說出來
- 我以後會和你說!
- Talk about it. Get it all out.
- I'll tell you later!
說所有的事情
Say everything now.
你就把所有事都說出來, 現在!快!快!
Just say everything now.
Now! Now! Now!
我會在下輩子告訴你, 當我們都變成貓的時候
I'll tell you in another life,
when we are both cats.
我無法相信你說了這些
I can't believe
you just said that.
這是我聽過的最棒的事
That is the greatest thing
that I've ever heard.
你這麼說可真是有趣啊
That's hilarious
that you said that.
看, 你竟然這麼說
See, that- You said that.
這就是我愛你的地方
That is what I love about you.
這真是太好玩了
That's hilarious.
我會在下輩子告訴你, 當我們都變成貓的時候
I'll tell you in another life,
when we are both cats.
貓!
Cats!
那麼, 我們就在這分開吧
Well, this is where I leave you.
我要送你到家門口
I'll walk you to your door.
- 我就住在轉角那邊
- 我有腳踏車
- I live just around the corner.
- I've got my bike here.
- 我更想走路
- 別費力了
- I'd rather walk.
- Don't be a drag.
你看不出來她想自己走?
Can't you see
she wants to go on her own?
閉嘴, 你醉了
Shut up. You're drunk.
我也許是白癡, 但我沒喝醉
I may be an idiot,
but I'm not drunk.
說真的, 我不需要你送我到家
Seriously, I don't need you
to walk me home.
謝謝你
Thank you.
好吧, 那麼, 我們再打給你
Okay, then.
So we'll call you.
好的, 到時我們去看場電影什麼的
We'll go catch a movie
or something.
那麼我們很快會再見的
So we'll meet up soon.
我們很快會再見的
We'll meet up soon.
我們會再打給你, 到時和我約會!
We'll call you again
to go out with me!
我們再打給你
We'll call you.
這玩得可真開心啊
It's been a real blast.
我祝你晚安
I bid you good evening.
等等, 等等, 你去哪?
Wait, wait.
Where are you going?
我的腳踏車, 就在那後面, 改天再找你玩
My bike- it's back over there.
We'll hang soon.
帶上你的面具如果你想的話, 我已經習慣了
And bring your mask if you want.
I'm getting used to it.
等一下
Wait a minute.
什麼?
What?
我不知道
I don't know.
你喝得有點多了, 有事明天打給我吧
You drank a little too much.
Call me tomorrow if you want.
我希望明天我就死了
Tomorrow I'll wish I was dead.
不, 你不希望, 你只需要睡個覺
No, you won't.
You just need to sleep.
什麼?
What?
車禍前你和茱莉.吉雅妮說了什麼?
What did you say to Julie Gianni
the night of the accident?
什麼?
What?
你和她說她是個..炮友
You told her
she was a fuck buddy.
沒有
Never.
她火得有點過頭了
She was a little more
than pissed about it.
你一直就為這破事耿耿於懷?
Have you been harboring
this shit all along?
我從沒和她說過
I never talked to her.
好吧
Whatever.
還有...
Anyway...
如果我不是那個說你長得不醜的人, 那我是誰?
who am I if I can't be the one
to tell you you're not ugly?
拜託
Come on.
勉強笑一個吧
Give me a courtesy laugh.
噢, 布萊恩, 我搞砸了
Oh, Brian, I'm so fucked up.
我真的搞砸了
I'm just so fucked up.
嘿, 布萊恩, 拜託
Hey, Brian, come on.
我們是最好的朋友!
We're best friends!
我們是哥們!
We're bros!
拜託, 老兄, 我們是哥們
Come on, man, we're bros.
睜開你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
這是個很爛的博同情的方式
This is a cheap ploy
for sympathy.
我沒事, 我沒事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
但起作用了, 起來吧
And it worked. Get up.
服你了
I agree.
這是個玩笑吧
This is a joke.
大衛, 我不想騙你
David, I'm not gonna lie to you.
我喜歡曾經的你
I liked the way you looked.
但...
But...
你得他媽的振作起來
you have to pull it
the fuck together.
否則的話, 我就會把那個人忘了
Because if not,
I'll forget the other guy.
你還知道那個人吧?  你
You know that other guy?
You.
我還是那個人, 我還和以前一樣
I'm still that guy.
聽好, 我骨子裡可不是個慈祥的人
I don't have a mother-savior bone
in my body.
和那無關, 你進來吧
It's not about that.
You are coming inside.
但如果事實證明這是個大錯...
But if this turns out
to be a big mistake...
我也能停止不去愛你...
I do have the ability
to fall out of love with you...
就像這樣簡單
like that.
我們一起創造了我們的世界
We created
our own world together.
- 我還和以前一樣
- 閉嘴
- I am still that guy.
- Shut up.
我們與世俗抗爭
Us versus them.
- 布萊恩在哪?
- 布萊恩?
- Where's Brian?
- Brian?
他跑去找你了, 不是嗎?
He went with you, didn't he?
我以為你們好上了
I thought you guys hooked up.
我真希望你從沒上那女孩的車
I wish you hadn't gotten
in the car with that girl.
索菲亞, 我...
Sofia, I-
你用眼神來道歉吧
Your eyes apologize better.
來吧
Come on.
天哪, 這將會令我的生活...
Holy God, this is going
to change my life...
發生翻天覆地的變化
in a zillion different ways.
我一定是瘋了
I must be nuts.
我們是天生一對
And we were quite a pair.
她相信我, 我也覺得...
Her believing in me,
me believing that...
我值得她這樣
I actually deserved it.
索菲亞...
Sofia...
我看你沒在浪費時間
I see you haven't
been wasting your time.
你還畫過其他的嗎?
Do you ever draw
anything else?
沒
No
昨晚睡了嗎?
Did you sleep last night?
沒, 沒睡
No, I did not sleep.
我今天得早走, 你得長話短說
Got to leave early today,
so you'll have to be brief.
那, 你能告訴我些什麼...
Now, what can you tell me...
是有關於這名字"艾莉"的?
about the name "Ellie"?
艾莉
Ellie.
是你認識的女孩? 你愛過的女孩?
Is that a girl you knew,
a girl you were in love with?
我只愛過一次
I've only been in love once.
很顯然, 昨晚你一直在喊她的名字
Apparently, you kept
repeating it last night.
你有睡覺, 大衛, 你的導師說你喊出來了
You did sleep, David.
Your advisor said you cried out.
- 你做了個噩夢
- 這一切都是噩夢
- You had a nightmare.
- Everything's a nightmare.
你在喊艾莉, 大衛, 記得發生了什麼嗎?
You cried out for Ellie, David.
Do you remember what happened?
我, 我不記得...
I, I no...
仔細想, 大衛
Dig deep, David.
仔細想
Dig deep.
你在喊艾莉, 你記得什麼嗎?
You cried out for Ellie.
What do you remember about Ellie?
給我看你的臉, 大衛
Show me your face, David.
幫我開啟那道門
Help me open the door.
你的確是出了車禍, 你的確被毀容了
It's true you had an accident.
It's true you were disfigured.
但你恢復了
But not anymore.
記得嗎?
Do you remember?
他們的確修復了你的臉
They did fix your face.
把面具摘掉, 大衛
Take off that mask, David.
你會看到下面那張完美的臉
You'll see your face
is perfect under there.
我從不相信醫生
I never trusted the doctors.
接下來的事更離奇
What happened next was surreal.
那個傲慢的混蛋, 波梅蘭茲醫生, 打電話給我
That same arrogant bastard,
Dr. Pomeranz, called me.
突然間他成為我的好朋友
Suddenly he was
my new best friend.
大衛, 嘿, 哥們
David! Hey, my brother.
對上次的談話我感到內疚
I felt really bad
about our last conversation.
他說他發明瞭一個新的整形方式...
He said he'd discovered a new form
of reconstructive surgery...
得到了來自柏林的醫生的幫助
with the help of a doctor
from Berlin.
你好
Hello.
接下來, 他們用不知什麼藥物給我全身麻醉...
Next thing I knew, they shot me
full of drugs I'd never heard of...
然後去手術室
and away we went.
如果上帝是我們中的一員
What if God was one of us
也就跟我們差不多
Just a slob like one of us
努力尋找回家的路
Trying to make his way home
他嗓子不錯
He's got a good voice.
Fifty-five.
那個概率, 他們說, 有三分之一可能...
The odds, they said,
were one in three...
會讓頭痛減輕50%...
that the headaches
could be reduced by 50 percent...
並且重建面部組織
and facial tissue
could be regenerated.
首次運用光纖重建眶骨膜的概念
The first to incorporate the concept
of endoscopic periorbital fiber optics.
等下哪吃去?
Where are we gonna eat later?
我無法告訴你他們做了什麼
I can't even tell you
what they did.
看起來就像科幻小說
It seemed like
science fiction to me.
你知道麥當娜有首歌"邊緣"
Madonna had that song,
"Borderline."
- 那首很好聽
- ...剪一下
- That was a hell of a song.
- And another snip.
我們完成後他就會變成個大帥哥
This is gonna be one
good-looking guy when I'm done.
顯然, 我很懷疑
Obviously, I was suspicious.
你不會嗎?
Wouldn't you be?
懷疑誰, 懷疑什麼?
Suspicious of whom, of what?
醫生...
Doc...
一旦你以時速八十英里沖下一座橋...
once you've been driven
off a bridge at 80 miles an hour...
不知為何你很難再快樂起來, 除非有十足把握
somehow you don't invite happiness in
without a full body search.
不怕煩你
At the risk of boring you...
我有不同的看法
I can present
the alternate argument.
我曾經認識一個人...
I once knew a guy...
他很孤單
who was a real loner.
直到他40歲某天...
One day he woke up at 40...
兩個女兒讓他覺得生命有了意義...
with two daughters that
lit up his life with purpose...
然後他開始經常去看學校的表演...
and he suddenly goes
to endless school plays...
9點半就回家聊天...
and he gets home at 9:20
for the evening discussion...
他過著最快樂的時光
and he has the time of his life.
他最喜歡的甲殼蟲人物曾經是約翰, 現在是保羅
His favorite Beatle was once John,
and now it's Paul.
我一直喜歡喬治
I always liked George.
這完全取決於個人, 不是嗎
It all depends on
the individual, doesn't it?
告訴我, 幸福對你來說是什麼?
Tell me,
what's happiness for you?
幸福對你來說是什麼, 大衛?
What's happiness to you, David?
- 可以問其他問題嗎?
- 你不給我看你的臉
- How 'bout another question?
- You won't show me your face.
給嗎?
Will you?
那就回到原來的談話吧
So back to the time line.
快, 讓我們快點結束這些
Hurry. Let's move through this.
什麼?
What?
你得把面具脫掉
You've got to take
the plates off.
我不想看到下面是什麼
I don't want to know
what's under here.
沒事的, 到時你就知道了
It's gonna be fine.
You'll see.
- 我明天再去
- 你今天就去
- I'll go tomorrow.
- Today.
我已經打給波梅蘭茲改到週三了
I already called Pomeranz
and switched it to Wednesday.
什麼?
What?
我希望你被前臺護士罵死
I hope that woman at the front desk
gave you shit about it.
改天沒事的,而且野馬汽車就要修好了
Another day won't matter.
Besides, the Mustang will be fixed.
原計劃是要開野馬去, 但沒好...
The plan was going in the Mustang.
The Mustang's not ready.
所以我們明天再去
So we'll go tomorrow
in the Mustang.
- 好吧
- 等它修好了我們就去
- Good.
- We'll go when it's fixed.
我知道問題是什麼...
I know that the problem...
你不會是在拖延你不敢面對的事吧
wouldn't be you delaying
something you were dreading.
不是
Couldn't be that.
當然不是
我是說
I mean-
我是說, 我同意
I mean, I agree.
我覺得這很重要...
I think it's very important...
開著...
to have...
心愛的車...
the right car...
帶你到...
to take you...
想去的地方...
where you want to go...
一天二十四小時...
24 hours a day.
有多糟?
How bad is it?
額, 你的耳朵處在正確的位置
Well, your ears
are in the right place.
其他的嘛...
And the rest of it...
總的來說不錯
is not too bad at all.
太完美了
It's perfect.
#鮑勃.狄倫的歌曲#
#music#
你愛我嗎?
Do you love me?
我是說, 真的愛嗎?
I mean, really love me?
因為如果你不愛的話...
Because if you don't...
我就只好殺了你
I'll just have to kill you.
我的下輩子
You see, my next life?
在我的下輩子...
In my next life...
我會投胎變成這裡的這顆痣
I'm gonna come back
as this mole right here.
說真的, 這顆痣
Seriously, this mole.
你只能穿比基尼和低胸的襯衣上班...
You'll have to wear bikini tops
to work and loose-fitting shirts...
這樣我才能透氣
so that I can breathe.
我愛你
I love you.
愛你
Love you.
我愛你
I love you.
我可以住在這裡
I can live right there.
這是個夢嗎?
Is this a dream?
絕對是
Absolutely.
[ 注:此場景來源於鮑勃.狄倫某張專輯的封面 ]
# special scene #
我們聊大事, 小事...
We talked about the big things,
the little things...
大事...
and the big things.
但事實上, 和索菲亞在一起...
But in truth, with Sofia...
什麼都不聊都很快樂
it was the in-between times.
她說什麼?
What did she say?
我聽不懂
I have no idea.
- 過得如何, 布萊恩?
- 很好
- How's things, Brian?
- Fine.
- 布萊恩, 過得如何?
- 別得意過頭了
- Brian, How's things?
- Don't flatter yourself.
我很好
I'm fine.
而且, 索菲亞很好, 但並不意味著獨一無二
Besides, Sofia is great
but by no means one of a kind.
她只是我一時的迷戀
She was a proximity infatuation.
別抄那句, 那是我的, 謝謝
And don't use that. It's mine.
Thanks.
你從哪弄的這像機?
Where'd you get this camera?
我的愛好, 你都不知道, 老兄
I'm into things.
You have no idea, my friend.
你沒事就好
Just as long as you're okay.
還有, 我們是朋友, 不是嗎?
And anyway,
we're friends, aren't we?
- 一直都是
- 沒錯
- Always.
- That's right.
你的臉怎麼了?
What's up with your face?
- 操!
- 什麼?
- Fuck!
- What?
有條縫還是什麼的裂開了!
There's a seam opening or something!
- 大衛.埃姆斯
- 你這混蛋
- David Aames.
- You fucking asshole.
我知道
I know.
我剛才在打呼嗎?
Was I snoring?
沒有,我覺得是我
No, I think it was me.
我只是口渴了
I was thirsty, that's all.
我夢見你了
I'm dreaming about you.
真想一直聽你"嗯"...
I could listen to you say "mmm"...
就這樣一輩子
for the rest of my life.
寶貝, 怎麼了?
Baby, what's wrong?
她在哪?
Where is she?
誰?
Who?
我是索菲亞
I'm Sofia.
現在, 我要確定我系了四次
Now, I'm gonna make sure
that I tie it four times.
你知道為什麼嗎, 茱莉?
You know why,Julie?
因為四次才有意義
Because four times
really means something.
大衛, 別傷害我
David, don't hurt me.
我怕了, 你真行
I'm freaked out.
It worked.
你知道你這樣是逃不了的...
You know you're not
gonna get away with this...
告訴我, 索菲亞在哪
so tell me now,
where is Sofia.
我就是索菲亞
I am Sofia.
- 索菲亞在哪?
- 我就是索菲亞!
- Where's Sofia?
- I am Sofia!
- 她在哪?
- 我就是!
- Where is she?
- I am Sofia!
我要叫員警, 你可以和他們說
I'm calling the police,
and you can tell it to them.
- 你從事故中生還了
- 什麼事故?
- You survived the accident.
- What accident?
那是誰的屍體? 是七矮人的董事會, 是嗎?
Whose body was it?
It was the Seven Dwarfs, wasn't it?
- 我沒有出事故
- 你還想搶走我的生活!
- I wasn't in an accident.
- You're trying to steal my life!
你當然沒有出事故
Of course you weren't
in an accident.
現在看來你他媽的是想殺我!
Now it's fucking attempted murder!
我是索菲亞, 求求你
I'm Sofia. Please.
和他們說去
Tell it to them.
我是大衛埃姆斯
This is David Aames.
我需要幫助
I need help.
有個入侵者, 我抓住了一個入侵者...
I have an intruder-
I've captured an intruder...
她闖進我家
who's entered my home.
天, 醒醒, 老兄
God. Wake up, man.
你是來真的?
Are you for real?
讓我在這等了三個鐘, 他們什麼都不說
Kept me waiting here for three hours.
They won't even tell me any news.
這些傢夥認為這些是我做的
These guys think that I had
something to do with this.
給我們一分鐘, 好嗎?
Give us a minute here, yeah?
拉爾森探員, 安德魯探員, 謝謝
Detective Larson, Detective Andrews,
thanks very much.
他們認為是我做的
They think that I had
something to do with this.
我會處理這些, 就像你爸會做的那樣
I'm gonna handle this exactly
the way your father would.
我都解決了
I've got it solved.
解決了?
You got it solved?
她在哪?
Where is she?
她會沒事的. 現在, 所有的檔案都會...
She's gonna be fine.
Now, this whole file is gonna-
幸好你在這兒, 老兄
Thank God you're here, man.
沒事了
It's okay.
- 我愛她
- 是的
- I love her.
- Yeah.
現在我要你看看這些照片, 然後我就銷毀它們
Right now I want you to look at these
photos, then I'm gonna destroy them.
索菲亞的證詞也在這兒
Sofia's testimony
is also in here.
也將不會存在
It won't exist.
她將不會再提起指控
She's not gonna press charges.
指控我?
Press charges against me?
大衛, 醒醒
David, wake up.
現在, 作為一個朋友...
Now, as a friend...
我覺得你應該看看你對索菲亞做了什麼
I think you should see
what you did to Sofia.
記者不會找到這裡,如果你快點走的話
The press won't get hold of this
if you get away quickly.
湯米, 這是茱莉, 這不是索菲亞
Tommy, this is Julie.
This is not Sofia.
這是茱莉.吉雅妮
This is Julie Gianni.
我沒對她做這些, 湯米, 有人在陷害我
I didn't do this to her.
Tommy, someone's setting me up.
大衛, 董事會和我會搞定這一切
David, the board and I
have taken care of everything.
好嗎, 他們很了不起, 真的了不起, 事實上
Okay, they've been really great,
really great, actually.
所有這些都將消失
All this is gonna disappear.
我們都會支援你, 包括董事會
We're all behind you,
even the board.
出去吧
Get out of here.
這是一次心靈的革命
This is a revolution
of the mind.
你還他媽裝悲傷的樣子!
You're in fuckin' sad shape!
別他媽的打女人
Don't fucking ever hit a girl.
打我, 別他媽的打女人
Hit me, but don't fucking ever
hit a girl!
聽我說, 那不是索菲亞
Listen to me.
It wasn't Sofia.
是茱莉
It was Julie.
- 是茱莉
- 是茱莉.吉雅妮?
- It was Julie.
- It was Julie Gianni.
是的
Yes.
所以索菲亞是被茱莉綁架了...
So Sofia was abducted by Julie...
然後茱莉扮成索菲亞
and now Julie is posing
as Sofia.
你喪心病狂了, 老兄
You're in O.J. land, man.
茱莉吉雅尼已經他媽的死了!
Julie Gianni is fucking dead!
我不管他們和你說了什麼,我可以向你保證茱莉還活著
I don't care what they told you,
I can assure you Julie Gianni is alive.
- 她還活著
- 我都沒和員警談過
- She is alive.
- I didn't talk to them.
我是和索菲亞談的
I talked to Sofia.
- 她在哪?
- 我剛送她回家
- Where is she?
- I just dropped Sofia off.
我看見你對她做的所有事
I saw everything you did to her.
我告訴你, 我沒那樣對她
Let me tell you something.
I did not do that to her.
看著我, 看著我的眼睛
Look at me.
Look me in the eye.
告訴我, 她就是那個你帶去派對的女孩
You tell me that's the girl
you brought to the party.
告訴我她就是你的夢中情人...
You tell me that
that's your dream girl...
你一時的迷戀
your proximity infatuation.
是的!
Yes!
而你把她從我這偷走了
And you stole her from me.
我唯一想要的女孩, 你把她偷走了
The one girl I really wanted,
and you took her from me.
你瘋了, 你不正常了, 老兄
You're insane.
You're losin' it, man.
- 你露出真面目了
- 噢, 是的
- You have revealed yourself.
- Oh, yeah.
我和他們一夥的
I'm with them.
你哪兒弄的大衣, 布萊恩?
Where'd you get the coat, Brian?
哪兒得到的像機?
Where'd you get the camera?
他們付你多少?
How much did they pay you?
聽著, 這將是我們最後一次談話
Listen to me, 'cause this is
the last time we're ever gonna speak.
我曾是你唯一的朋友
I was your only friend.
你終於露出真面目了
You have revealed yourself to me.
有問題嗎?
Problems?
我沒心情胡扯, 所以拜託你...
I'm in no mood to be fucked with,
so do yourself a favor-
我能解釋所有這一切, 大衛
There's an explanation
for all this, David.
我們互相認識, 你在網路上找到我
You and I know each other.
You found me on the Internet.
我是來這幫你, 大衛
I'm here to help you, David.
你他媽的是誰? 為什麼跟蹤我?
Who the fuck are you?
Why are you following me?
首先, 你一定要冷靜下來
First of all, it's very important
that you calm down.
冷靜?
Calm down?
冷靜
Calm down.
你必須克服你的恐懼, 做回自己
You must overcome your fears
and regain control.
再次掌控你的生活, 大衛
Take ahold of your life again,
David.
就像握住那酒杯一樣容易
It's as easy
as holding that glass.
如果我告訴你會怎樣...你可以控制...
What if I were to tell you
that you can take control...
所有的這些, 一切
of all of this, everything?
甚至我
Even me.
聽著, 我不是同性戀, 好嗎?
Look, I'm straight. Okay?
大衛, 看看這些人
David, look at all these people.
他們好像都在聊天, 不是嗎?
Seems as though they're just
all chatting away, doesn't it?
是的
Yeah.
- 和你沒關係
- 沒錯
- Nothing to do with you.
- No.
但是...
And yet...
也許他們在這裡, 只是因為你想要他們在這裡
maybe they're only here because
you wanted them to be here.
你就是他們的上帝
You are their god.
不止這樣, 你可以讓他們服從你或毀了你
Not only that, but you can make them
obey you or even destroy you.
好吧, 我想讓他們做的就是他媽的閉嘴
Well, what I'd love for them to do
is shut the fuck up.
尤其是你
Especially you.
你看
You see?
我們簽了一份合約, 大衛
You and I
signed a contract, David.
餐館裡的人是誰? 他是誰?
Who is the man in the restaurant?
Who is it?
我不知...
I can't-
你能分清夢境和現實嗎?
Can you tell the difference
between dreams and reality?
- 當然了, 你能嗎?
- 想想看
- Of course. Can you?
- Think about it.
用腦子想
Think with your head.
你簽了一份合同...
You signed a contract...
到底簽了沒有?
did you not?
我簽了某樣東西
I signed something.
餐館裡的那個人也在嗎?
Was the man
in the restaurant there?
- 操..
- 順從你身體的抵抗
- Fuck-
- Accept your body's resistance.
用你的腦子想
Let your head answer.
簽這合約, 大衛
Sign the contract, David.
- 是的
- 這就對了
- Yes.
- That's right.
艾莉是誰?
Who is Ellie?
- 我不知道什麼是真的
- 那晚發生了什麼?
- I don't know what's real.
- What happened that night?
- 某個人死了
- 我不想記得
- Somebody died.
- I don't want to remember.
你掌握著解救自己的關鍵
You hold the keys
to this prison.
- 那不是索菲亞
- 那是誰?
- It wasn't Sofia.
- Who was it?
- 不是
- 那是誰?
- No.
- Who was it?
我好害怕你這麼厲害
I'm afraid of
how powerful this is.
你想要說出來, 不是嗎, 大衛?
You wanna let it out,
don't you, David?
你就要說了
You're about to tell me.
告訴我...
Tell me...
你的內心和靈魂不會允許你忘記
what your heart and soul
will not allow you to forget.
你殺了索菲亞嗎?
Did you kill Sofia?
我以為你是個破壞者
I thought you were a vandal.
你是誰?
Who are you?
我是索菲亞
I'm Sofia.
你不是...
You are not...
索菲亞
Sofia.
你不是..索菲亞
You are not...Sofia.
我是索菲亞
I'm Sofia.
算了
Whatever.
我們又會在一起了
We're gonna be together again.
你會忘了茱莉, 和我在一起
You're gonna forget about Juliana
and we're gonna be together.
我不會再怕你了
I'm not gonna be afraid
of you anymore.
我去給你拿冷毛巾, 馬上回來
I'm gonna get you a cold towel.
I'll be right back.
我愛你
I love you.
延遲享樂者
Pleasure delayer.
索菲亞?
Sofia?
我是索菲亞
I am Sofia.
我愛你
I love you.
我太想念你了
Oh, I missed you so much.
你到哪去了?
Where were you?
算了
Forget it.
我不必知道
I don't need to know.
這沒什麼
It doesn't matter.
只要告訴我你愛我
Just tell me that you love me.
我愛你
I love you.
幸福對你來說是什麼, 大衛?
What is happiness to you, David?
對我來說...
For me...
就是在這兒和你在一起
it's being here with you.
這他媽的...
What the fuck...
是怎麼回事?
is happening?
這他媽的怎麼回事?
What is fucking happening?
大衛真是個可愛的小孩
David was a real delight
as a child.
噢, 天哪!
Oh, God!
我很害怕你真厲害!
I'm so afraid
of how powerful this is!
噢, 大衛!
Oh, David!
紅禮服, 系帶鞋?
Red dress, strappy shoes?
這是我聽過的最棒的話
That is the greatest thing
I've ever heard.
下輩子當我們都是貓的時候
In another life
when we are both cats.
怎麼回事?
What's happening?
嘿, 老兄, 怎麼回事?
Hey, man, what's happening?
你這婊子!
You bitch!
我不想看見你的臉!
I don't wanna see your face!
是我幹的, 對吧?
I did it, didn't I?
但我沒覺得我殺過人
But I don't feel
like I killed someone.
- 大衛...
- 我覺得...
- David...
- I feel like...
- 那個男人是誰...
- 我像在夢中
- who was the man...
- I'm in a dream.
餐館裡的那個?
at the restaurant?
有時候...
Sometimes...
大腦的行為讓你覺得就像在做夢
the mind behaves
as if it were in a dream.
面孔變換, 一個人變成另一個
Faces change.
People become other people.
潛意識是很強烈的
The subconscious
is a powerful thing.
你對茱莉沒興趣, 不是嗎?
You treated Julie carelessly,
didn't you?
你對她抱有負罪感...
Your feelings of responsibility
or guilt over Julie...
很容易把索菲亞當成茱莉
might have easily
turned Sofia into Julie.
你知道精神錯亂是什麼嗎?
Do you know what derangement is?
我需要你説明
I need your help.
我所知道的就是,你殺了你的女朋友...
All I know is,
you killed your girlfriend...
我不知道你想的是什麼
and I don't know
what's in your mind.
我需要你説明
I need your help.
我會一直跟進這案子如果可以的話, 但我們沒時間了
I would work on this case forever
if I could, but we're out of time.
你會以什麼做辯詞?
What will you plead?
暫時性神經失常
Temporary derangement.
這是最好的說法
That's your best chance.
我不認為他們會相信我
I don't think they'll believe me.
你相信什麼?
What do you believe?
無論相信什麼, 我很關心你
Believe it or not,
I care about you.
你對我來說已經像家人一樣
You've become like family to me.
我不想放棄你, 大衛, 但我需要瞭解更多
I don't want to give up on you,
David, but I needed more.
我需要...
I needed-
我需要一個答案
I needed an answer.
我的意思是, 我覺得會有一個更好的理由...
I mean, I even thought there was
more than a good chance...
有人在陷害你
somebody was playing
a trick on you.
也許是董事會
Maybe it was the board.
但這已經超過我的職責
But I can't exceed my duties.
我只是個心理學家
I'm just a psychologist.
我也得走了
And I have to go now.
審訊的時候再見?
Will I see you at the trial?
不, 我只...
No, I'm-
我只算是個開場
I'm just the opening act.
"讓您安心是我們的專長, 這是我們生命延續的信條"
Reassurance is our specialty.
That is the Life Extension credo.
"班尼是一條曾被凍了三個月的小狗..."
Benny is a dog who was frozen
for three months...
"解凍後過上了正常的生活"
and thawed out
to live a normal life.
"生命延續也能用在人類的形式上"
Life Extension can translate
to the human form too.
"你如何辦到這些?"
How do you accomplish
such a thing?
"72個冷凍的病人..."
Seventy-two cryonized patients...
"目前保存在新不倫瑞克省我們的收容中心裡"
are currently held at our facility
in New Brunswick.
"我們擁有世界上最好的科技人員"
And we feature the finest scientific
technicians on the planet.
麥凱布醫生!
McCabe!
回來!
Come back!
LE (發音近似Ellie--艾莉)
LE
生命延續公司
Life Extension Corporation,
please.
- 我能幫你嗎?
- LE
- Can I help you?
我們有法院許可
We hold a court order.
我想我之前來過這裡
I think I've been here before.
她叫莉比
Her name is Libby.
早上好, 麥凱布先生
Good morning, Mr. McCabe.
我是莉比, 讓我為你效勞
I'm Libby.
I'm here to assist you.
他是我兒子, 他很害羞
He's my son.
He's very shy.
你不是媒體或法律協會的, 是吧?
You're not with the media or a part
of any legal consortium, correct?
不是
No.
歡迎來到生命延續
Welcome to Life Extension.
看一下我們的簡介, 請跟我來
Take a look at our proposal.
Please follow me.
你可以在外面等著
You can wait out here.
你們會去見麗蓓嘉.迪爾伯恩...
You'll be meeting
Rebecca Dearborn...
我心目中的榜樣
my personal role model.
我不想再要痛苦, 我已經受夠了
I didn't need the pain anymore.
I already experienced that.
他們想要你倒下死掉, 生命延續想要你生存
They want you to lay down and die.
Life Extension wants you to live.
我不認為上帝不同意這麼做
I don't think that God
disapproves of this.
"冰凍: 覺醒的歷程...
"Cryonization.:
a journey of reawakening...
首先以超低溫保存人體"
after the preservation of the human
body at extremely low temperatures."
他們也曾嘲笑過儒勒·凡爾納 (科幻小說之父)
They laughed at Jules Verne too.
大衛, 你不是...
You are not-
麥凱布先生, 你好, 我是麗蓓嘉.迪爾伯恩
Mr. McCabe, how are you?
I'm Rebecca Dearborn.
生命延續, 或者我們更喜歡稱為LE...
Life Extension,
or LE as we like to refer to it...
是對未來的展望...
is a glimpse of the future.
是一張入場券...
It's a ticket.
非膚淺的, 而是極有意義的...
Not in the juvenile sense, but
in the deeply meaningful sense...
深入人類內心的探索
that can only be born
in the human heart.
人體的DNA代碼已被破解
The DNA codes of the human body
have been broken.
很快, 心臟病, 癌症...
Soon, heart ailments, cancer...
很多都會成為過去
so much more
will be a thing of the past.
非常簡單,你的痛苦, 你的不滿...
Very simply,
your anguish, your discontent...
甚至你的死亡, 都不再發生...
even your death
is no longer necessary...
...於傳統的概念裡
in a traditional sense.
無論是什麼疾病掩藏在那面具後面, 它都是暫時的
Whatever malady hides behind
that mask, it's temporary.
在你死去一小時內...
Within an hour of your passing...
LE將把你的身體轉移到一個容器裡...
LE will transfer your body
to a vessel...
在那裡你將被密封, 並用-196度低溫冰凍
where you will be sealed and frozen
at 196 degrees below zero.
斷電, 地震...
Power outtages, earthquakes-
沒有任何事會影響你的掛起式休眠
nothing will affect
your suspension hibernation.
你和這些人簽了合約嗎, 大衛?
Did you sign a contract
with these people, David?
"清晰夢境"
"Lucid Dream"
清晰夢境選項是什麼?
What's the Lucid Dream option?
很好的選擇
Good choice.
清晰夢境, 是LE最新的服務選項
The Lucid Dream
is Life Extension's newest option.
需要額外付一點錢...
For a little extra...
我們提供的這種冰凍結合了...
we offer the cryonic union...
科技和享樂的效果
of science and entertainment.
"冰凍樂"
"Cryo-tainment."
也許這解釋會有幫助
Some find this presentation
helpful.
# 有一個宇宙 #
I have a universe
# 在我心中 #
Inside me
現代人一生的寫照
Portrait of a modern human life.
美國, 男性...
American, male...
出生然後死亡
birth and death.
想像你正承受絕症之痛
Imagine that you are suffering
from a terminal illness.
你想被冰凍, 但你更想被復活...
You'd like to be cryonized,
but you'd rather be resurrected...
繼續目前你所熟悉的生活
to continue your own life
as you know it now.
LE會滿足你的要求
LE offers you the answer.
一旦復活...
Upon resurrection...
你將繼續以永恆的狀態...
you will continue
in an ageless state...
...保持下去, 那時的生活...
preserved
but living in the present...
就是你所選擇的未來
with a future
of your choosing.
死亡將從你的記憶中抹去
Your death will be wiped
from your memory.
你的生活將會是一個現實的藝術品...
Your life will continue as
a realistic work of art...
...由你所描繪, 每個時刻...
painted by you,
minute to minute...
...你將活在夏日的浪漫戀情中
and you'll live it with the
romantic abandon of a summer day...
感覺有如你所喜愛的經典電影...
with the feeling
of a great movie...
或流行音樂一樣
or a pop song you always loved-
有關這是如何發生的記憶...
with no memory
of how it all occurred...
都不會被保存下來...
save for the knowledge...
一切都只是更完美
that everything simply improved.
有任何疑惑的地方...
In any instance
of discontent...
你都會獲得技術支援
you'll be visited
by technical support.
一切指日可待
It's all just around the corner.
在不久的將來, 另一個篇章將無縫的展開
The day after tomorrow,
another chapter begins seamlessly.
一個逼真的夢境
A living dream.
生命延續將向您提供
[ 清晰夢境 ]
Life Extension's promise to you.
"Lucid Dream"
生命, 第二章
Life, part two.
一個逼真的夢境
A living dream.
"死亡將從你的記憶中抹去"
"Your death will be
wiped from your memory."
我覺得我錯過了的這篇的報導
I guess I missed that one
in USA Today.
夢境
A dream.
要是出錯了呢?
What if there was a mistake?
美夢變成了噩夢怎麼辦?
What if the dream
became a nightmare?
當然你的潛意識總在幹擾你
Of course your subconscious
can always play tricks on you.
它是個力量很強的東西
The subconscious
is a very powerful thing.
你和這些人簽合同了嗎, 大衛?
Did you sign a contract
with these people, David?
這是個嚴肅的生意
But this is a serious business.
"清晰夢境"值得去冒險
The Lucid Dream
is worth the risk.
生命不去追求夢想那會是什麼?
And what is any life
if not the pursuit of a dream?
夢想著和平...
The dream of peace...
夢想著成就...
the dream of achievement...
夢想有人和你說那些話語...
the dream of hearing someone
say these words...
當你聽到她們真心的說...
when they really,
truly mean them.
我愛你, 大衛
I love you, David.
我愛你
I love you.
釋放自己, 大衛
Roam free, David.
我們大多數人的一生...
Most of us
live our whole lives...
都沒有真正的冒險是屬於自己的
without any real adventure
to call our own.
這令人難以理解
It's hard to comprehend.
"但人們也嘲笑過儒勒.凡爾納" (大衛剛說過)
"But they laughed
at Jules Verne too."
這...
This...
是一場革命...
is a revolution...
...關於心靈的
of the mind.
我要醒過來!
I wanna wake up!
技術員!
Tech support!
嘿, 怪物!
Hey! Face!
這是個噩夢!
It's a nightmare!
技術員!
Tech support!
大衛.埃姆斯
David Aames.
我想是時候正式的自我介紹了
I think it's time we had
a proper reintroduction.
我是艾德蒙.文圖拉, 來自綠洲計畫
I'm Edmund Ventura
from the Oasis Project.
原名生命延續, LE
Formerly Life Extension, LE.
- 技術員
- 是的
- Tech support.
- Yes.
是的, 我是你的技術支援...
Yes, I'm your tech support...
我們第一次見面是在150年前
and we first met
150 years ago.
哇, 靠
Oh, shit.
你向我推銷清晰夢境
You sold me the Lucid Dream.
他媽的發生了什麼事?
What the hell happened?
我試圖在酒吧裡警告你
I tried to warn you in the bar.
我告訴你必須運用控制, 一切取決於你的意志
I told you you must exercise control,
that it all depended on your mind.
所有這些...
All of this...
都是你的想像創造出來的
everything is your creation.
現在我們將迎來你抉擇的時刻
And now we're heading toward
your true moment of choice.
抉擇的時刻?
True moment of choice?
是的
Yes.
我什麼時候開始清晰夢境的?
When did the Lucid Dream begin?
記得夜總會那天嗎?
Remember the day
of the nightclub?
我們很快會再見的
We'll meet up soon.
那晚, 索菲亞離開後你睡倒在路邊...
That night, after Sofia left you and
you fell asleep on the pavement...
就是那個時刻, 你選擇作為拼接
that was the moment
that you chose for the splice.
- 拼接?
- 拼接
- Splice?
- Splice.
記憶中真實生活的結束, 清晰夢境的開始
The end of your real life and
the beginning of LE's Lucid Dream.
對接過去了很多很多年...
A splice of many, many years
which passed...
期間你都是在冰凍和夢中
while you were frozen
and dreaming.
那個時刻你從街上醒來...
From the moment
you woke up on that street...
就沒有任何傳統觀念上的真實了
nothing was real
in the traditional sense.
睜開你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
你的清晰夢境一直被"生命延續"監控...
Your Lucid Dream
is monitored by Life Extension...
一個專家小組在跟蹤你的每個想法...
and a panel of experts who are
following your every thought...
包括這個時刻
even at this moment.
抱歉, 搞得你很頭大
Forgive me.
I'm blowing your mind.
我可不喜歡這麼高
I'm not a big fan of heights.
我知道
I know.
我們從你記憶中消除了實際發生的事
We erased what really happened
from your memory.
- 消除?
- 是替換...
- Erased?
- Replaced.
...用一個更好的生活
By a better life...
在這個...
under these...
美麗的...莫內所鍾愛的天空下
beautiful, Monet-like skies.
我母親的最愛
My mother's favorite.
更好的生活...因為你擁有索菲亞
A better life
because you had Sofia.
你用年輕時的記憶構築著你的夢
You sculpted your Lucid Dream out
of the iconography of your youth.
比如一張曾讓你感動的唱片封面
An album cover
that once moved you.
唱片封面?
An album cover?
"有些事...
There are some things...
你還沒到年齡去瞭解"
that you're not old enough
to understand just yet.
一些電影向你展示了父親是怎樣的...
A movie you saw once that showed you
what a father could be like...
...或者愛是怎樣的
or what love could be like.
而某個女孩...
This was a kind woman...
特別的...
an individual...
...超過你的想像
more than your equal.
你只在現實中認識她, 但在夢中...
You barely knew her in real life,
but in your Lucid Dream...
...她是你的精神寄託
she was your savior.
現實中我怎麼了? 發生了些事
What happened in my real life?
Something happened.
你消除了什麼?
What did you erase?
你真想知道?
Do you really want to know?
把一切告訴我
Tell me everything.
夜總會的第二天早晨, 你在街上醒來...
The morning after the nightclub,
you woke up on that street...
一個人還帶著宿醉
hung over and alone.
你站起來, 然後離開
You got up, walked away.
你再也沒見過索菲亞
You never saw Sofia again.
我沒殺索菲亞
I didn't kill Sofia.
沒有
No.
你為了控制公司與董事會對抗
You battled your board
for control of the company...
最後是湯瑪斯.提普, 你父親的朋友...
and in the end it was Thomas Tipp,
your father's friend...
...你保住他工作的那個人...
the man whose job you saved...
...讓公司回到你的控制
who wrenched the company
back into your control.
湯米
Tommy.
可是後來...
But then...
有人...死了
somebody died.
你思念索菲亞
You longed for Sofia.
與世隔絕數月
You shut yourself away for months.
你感到孤獨
You were alone.
你再也忍受不了頭痛的痛苦
You couldn't stand
the pain anymore, the headaches.
你幾乎崩潰
You could barely function.
我在網路上找到你
I found you on the Internet.
我和你簽了份合同然後...
I signed a contract with you,
and then-
我記得了
I remember.
有人死了
Somebody died.
那就是我
It was me.
十二月晚些時候...
And on a day in late December...
你把自己交給我們
you gave yourself to us.
你進入了休眠的狀態
You're now in a suspended state.
你的朋友布萊恩.謝比在你的舊屋子舉辦了三天紀念會
Your friend Brian Shelby threw a
three-day memorial in your old home.
他是個真正的朋友
He was a true friend.
大家都想念你, 大衛
You were missed, David.
索菲亞始終沒能從悲傷中恢復過來
It was Sofia
who never fully recovered.
她似乎是最瞭解你的人...
It was she who somehow
knew you best...
和你一樣, 她永遠也忘不了那個晚上...
and like you, she never
forgot that one night...
真愛幾乎就要出現
where true love seemed possible.
往往最重要的, 大衛...
Consequences, David.
...都是那些小事
It's the little things.
小事
The little things.
根本就沒什麼大事, 是吧?
There's nothing bigger,
is there?
你的潛意識的確造成了麻煩
Your subconscious
did create problems.
美夢變成了噩夢
Your dream
turned into a nightmare.
不過現在問題解決了
The glitch has been corrected.
所以我只要想像某個事物
So all I have to do
is imagine something.
比如, 如果我要...
Like, if I wanted...
麥凱布現在就回來
McCabe to come back right now-
聽著
Listen to me.
這些人很危險
These people are dangerous.
我們有麻煩了, 現在必須離開這屋頂
We're in trouble.
We need to get off this roof now.
現在我們暫停...
We're now on pause...
你將回到你的夢中
and you're about to return
to your Lucid Dream.
所有事都會更新...
With all the upgrades...
你不會記得所有這些...
you won't remember any of this...
也不會為這次技術支援付費
nor will you be charged
for technical support.
現在就是你抉擇的時刻
It's now your moment of choice.
你可以回到夢中過著美麗的生活...
You can return to your Lucid Dream
and live a beautiful life...
...和索菲亞或者你希望的任何人
with Sofia or whomever you wish...
或者你可以選擇這外面的世界
or you can choose
the world out there.
"外面的世界"
"The world out there."
你可以讓我回到...
And you can bring me back...
就像小狗班尼那樣?
just like Benny the dog?
是的
Yes.
就像小狗班尼那樣
Just like Benny the dog.
當然現在你的臉和身體都能被復原
Your face and body
can be fixed now, of course.
但現實事情會大不一樣
But things
are very different now...
你的財富不會一直持有
and your finances
won't last long.
觀察小組正等待你的決定
Your panel of observers
are waiting for you to choose.
這沒有任何保證...
There are no guarantees...
但記住...
but remember...
即使是在未來...
even in the future...
甜蜜也不會是甜蜜...
the sweet is never as sweet...
...如果沒嘗過心酸的話
without the sour.
我該怎麼醒過來?
How do I wake up?
這是你決定的
The decision is yours.
這個地方也是我選擇的, 不是嗎?
And I chose this scenario,
didn't I?
是的, 去面對你僅存的對高度的恐懼
Yes, to face your last
remaining fear of heights.
大衛, 別信他們
David, don't listen to him.
你說得對, 這都是七矮人, 這是個圈套
You were right. This is
the seven dwarfs. It's a setup!
你不能相信他
You can't trust him.
別為他感到不爽, 大衛, 這人是你創造出來的
Don't feel bad for him, David.
This winning man is your creation.
他本能的去爭取他的存在, 但他不是真的
It's in his nature to fight for
his existence, but he's not real.
我是真的
I'm real.
我有兩個女兒...
I have two daughters...
你知道的
and you know that.
她們的名字是什麼?
What are their names?
我是真的
I'm real.
我只是家庭娛樂的犧牲品?
I'm mortality
as home entertainment?
這不可能是我的命運
This cannot be the future!
可能嗎?
Can it?
再見
Good-bye.
這是一場自我覺醒的偉大旅程
It's been a brilliant journey
of self-awakening.
現在你只需要問問自己
And now you've simply got to
ask yourself this-
幸福對你來說是什麼, 大衛?
What is happiness to you, David?
我想過真實的生活
I want to live a real life.
我不想再做夢
I don't want to dream any longer.
最後還有什麼願望嗎?
Any last wishes?
就讓他們知道我的想法吧
Let them out there
read my mind.
祝你好運, 大衛
I wish you well, David.
瞧瞧我們
Look at us.
我被冰凍, 你卻死了
I'm frozen, and you're dead.
而我愛你
And I love you.
這是個問題
It's a problem.
我上了那輛車後就失去了你
I lost you
when I got in that car.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你還記得曾經對我說過的嗎?
Do you remember
what you told me once?
每一分鐘...
That every passing minute...
都有可能會改變一切
is another chance
to turn it all around.
我會再找到你的
I'll find you again.
下輩子我會再遇見你...
I'll see you in another life...
當我們都是貓的時候
when we are both cats.
放輕鬆, 大衛
Relax, David.
睜開你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
追悼會上那首歌名是:
Ladies And Gentlemen We Are Floating In Space
(我們漂浮在宇宙中)